<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<newsarticle>
 
  <author>David Allen</author>
  <headline>Long term investors remain steady in turbulent market</headline>
  <date>11/10/1999 00:00:00</date>
  <targets>growth</targets>
  <language>de_DE</language>

  <content><![CDATA[
<p>
QUINCY, MA/November 11-We've noted the extraordinary returns posted by the Dow Jones Industrial Average the past few years. However, these figures are far in excess of how stocks have performed over any reasonably long time frame. In Stocks for the Long Run, economist Jeremy Siegel examined stock returns all the way back to 1802 and shows that by investing in the long-term will help your investments remain steady in turbulent markets like those of the past year.
</p>

<p>
For the entire period from 1802 through 1997, the stock market's compound annual return was 8.4%. During the modern financial era, from 1926 to 1997, the total annual compound return for stocks was somewhat higher at 10.6%. Some investors may object that the Depression-era stock market of the 1930s was an anomaly that is unlikely to be repeated. Fair enough. If we look at just the period following World War II (1946 - 1997), we see that the total return was 12.2% - a bit higher but still a long way from the returns of the 1995 - 1997 period. Those years have been truly exceptional, and it would be a mistake to base any long-term investment program on them.
</p>

<p>
But here is what you can do:
</p>

<p>
Maintain a clear distinction between long-term and short-term investments - There's a trap that many investors fall into as the market surges upward month after month. It all seems so easy, so automatic. In such circumstances, it may be tempting to withdraw funds from your money market accounts or refinance your house to invest in stocks. Think very carefully before you do these things. You still need a short-term emergency source of cash. You still need a house. Both could be jeopardized if you plunge into the market at the wrong time. Remember that market risk increases as you shorten your investment time frame. If it's money you might need in less than five years, you're probably better off leaving it where it is.
</p>

<p>
Decide how much risk you can tolerate - For planning purposes, it's best to assume that the market will continue to operate as it has in the past, and that you will be faced with one or more substantial declines during your investing lifetime. You should know now how you will react to those declines.
</p>

<p>
In order to receive the benefit of long-term returns, you need to be invested through the market's valleys as well as its peaks. Resolve now to do so - and mean it. If, after an honest self-appraisal, you feel that you can't stand the risk inherent in the stock market's short-term swings, consider some of the suggestions for diversification mentioned below. Your Financial Advisor can tailor an investment program designed to meet your needs.
</p>

<p>
Diversify your investments among different industries, asset classes and geographical areas - Diversification simply means having investments that are not synchronized, so that some move up when others move down. An example would be buying the stock of an airline and an oil company; one is hurt by higher oil prices, while the other is helped. Other examples include holding bonds and money market assets as well as stocks, and investing a portion of your funds overseas. Diversification achieves two goals. It helps cut risk and actually increases the expected compound return of your portfolio.
</p>

<p>
Understand the power of dividends to contribute significantly to your total returns over the long run - Your total return from an investment is comprised of capital appreciation and dividend or interest income. Capital appreciation comes from changes in the price of the investment. Dividends are payments to shareholders made by many companies. Most people assume that the bulk of the returns from stock investments comes from capital appreciation. In fact, from 1929 to 1997 the contributions of capital appreciation and dividends to total return were roughly equal, and the percentage contribution from dividends was even greater when measured on an inflation-adjusted basis. Not all stocks pay dividends, and there may be times when you are willing to forego a dividend if a stock looks particularly promising. But dividend-paying stocks can be a powerful addition to your investment arsenal, especially if you reinvest all of your dividends.
</p>

<p>
Keep an eye on the effects of taxes - Tax considerations strongly support a buy-and-hold strategy, as opposed to frequent in-and-out trading. The longer you hold a stock, the longer you can postpone paying capital gains taxes on your profits. Second, the tax laws are specifically designed to benefit long-term investors. Assets held for 12 months or less are taxed at the same rate as your income, up to 39.6%. However, assets held for more than 12 months are generally taxed at a capital gains tax rate of 20%. In addition, dividends and interest are taxed as ordinary income, which means that they may be subject to tax rates as high as 39.6%. It may make sense, therefore, to keep high-dividend stocks in an IRA or some other tax-sheltered account, and growth stocks, which frequently have negligible dividends and none at all in many cases, in a regular (taxable) account. Finally, remember to maintain a balanced view of things. While tax considerations should never be the sole factor influencing your investment decisions, they should be weighed carefully.
</p>

<p>
Diversify across time by investing on a regular schedule - If you invest a large sum of money in the market all at once, you're effectively putting all your financial eggs in one basket. If the time at which you choose to invest your money happens to be an inopportune one, you could expose yourself to considerable risk.
</p>
]]>
</content>
<status>draft</status>
<goLiveDate>11/11/1999 00:00:00</goLiveDate>
<authorId>jack</authorId>
</newsarticle>
<!-- @version $Id: //product/DSS/version/10.0.3/release/DSSJ2EEDemo/j2ee-apps/QuincyFunds/web-app/repositories/News/de_DE/longterm.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
