<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<AtgNews>
<story>
<id>009</id>
<category>Financial News</category>
<headline>
  Construction Spending Rises 0.7 Percent</headline>
<summary>
  Construction activity rises for the fourth straight month</summary>
<content>WASHINGTON - Construction activity rose for the fourth straight month in June as spending for public building projects increased by the largest amount in nearly a year.

The Commerce Department reported Wednesday that spending for all building projects rose by 0.7 percent in June.

The June increase was the fourth straight jump in building activity and was the largest since a 1.3 percent rise in July 2000.

Building activity in May, which originally was reported as a 0.3 percent increase, was revised up to an increase of 0.4 percent.

The government reported last week that the overall economy was staying out of a recession in the April-June quarter with the gross domestic product managing to rise at a rate of 0.7 percent.

The Bush administration and many private economists believe the country is poised to continue its rebound in growth in the second half of this year, helped by the tax rebate checks now arriving in the mail and aggressive credit easing by the Federal Reserve.

Many economists believe the Fed will cut rates when the central bank next meets on Aug. 21.

For June, the overall raise in construction activity reflected strength in both private sector work and government projects.

Government spending rose by 0.6 percent at an annual rate, the biggest increase since June 2000. Spending rose for schools and other public buildings while a sizable increase of 1.2 percent for highway projects.

Spending in the private sector was up by 0.7 percent in June. That represented the highest level for private sector spending since last November.

Nonresidential construction rose slightly in June with strength in factory construction offsetting declines in office buildings and hotels.
</content>
</story>



</AtgNews>
<!-- @version $Id: //app/portal/version/10.0.3/xmlfeed/xmlfeed.war/xml/LocalBusinessNews/010.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
