<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<newsarticle>

  <author>Henry Kaiser</author>
  <headline>Congress estimates that the cost of fixing the Y2K bug has risen to <dollar/>6.8 billion</headline>
  <date>11/13/1999 00:00:00</date>
  <targets>market</targets>
  <language>en_US</language>

  <content><![CDATA[
<p>
WASHINGTON, DC, U.S.A. (NB) -- Newsbytes. Like a credit card bill spiraling out of control because of interest payments, Uncle Sam's bill to fix the federal government's Year 2000 (Y2K) problem has risen by <dollar/>400 million to <dollar/>6.8 billion, with the Transportation Department, Health and Human Services, and the Agency for International Development making inadequate progress. The Associated Press quoted an Office of Management and Budget (OMB) quarterly report as saying four out of five of its almost 6,400 computer systems are have been fixed, replaced or determined not to be vulnerable, ahead of a self-imposed deadline of March 31. OMB also said it had expected the <dollar/>400 million increase, saying some systems needed to be reworked after initial Y2K repairs were completed. Five of the seven most important computer systems in place at the Agency for International Development will not meet the March 31 deadline, the AP quoted OMB as saying, because a problem believed to have been fixed was actually still there. But five of the largest agencies have already completed work: Environmental Protection Agency, National Science Foundation, Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Small Business Administration and Social Security Administration.
</p>

<p>
In OMB's last quarterly report last December, the agency had upped its Y2K fix costs <dollar/>1 billion to <dollar/>6.4  billion, even tough the agency reported significant progress since the third quarter of 1998 (Newsbytes, Dec. 9, 1998). At that time, OMB said that 61 percent of the federal government's 6,696 "mission critical systems" are compliant, compared to 50 percent in August. In its August report, the OMB listed 7,343 "mission critical systems," but said that several of those systems would be scuttled.
</p>
]]>
</content>
<status>returned</status>
<authorId>jack</authorId>
<editorId>jack</editorId>
<goLiveDate>12/1/1999 14:00:00</goLiveDate>
<notes>Jack, check your figures and get this back to me today.</notes>
</newsarticle>
<!-- @version $Id: //product/DSS/version/10.0.3/release/DSSJ2EEDemo/j2ee-apps/QuincyFunds/web-app/repositories/News/en_US/congress.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
