<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<newsarticle>
  
  <author>Leo Smith</author>
  <headline>Dow gains 91.35 in heavy trading yesterday</headline>
  <date>11/11/1999 00:00:00</date>
  <targets>market</targets>
  <language>en_US</language>
  
  <content><![CDATA[
<p>
NEW YORK (Reuters) - Stocks rose Thursday after more good news on inflation
suggested that interest rates will hold steady.
</p>

<p>
At 11:55 a.m. EDT, the Dow Jones industrial average was up 91.35 points, or 0.83 percent, to 11,091.72. The Nasdaq Composite index gained 22.96 points, or 0.88 percent, at 2,629.50.
</p>

<p>
The government reported the Producer Price Index rose 0.5 percent in April, but excluding food and energy, prices edged up only 0.1 percent, which was in line with expectations. "Sure, it was up 0.5 percent, but it was all energy," said Quentin Tip, analyst, Quincy Funds, Co.
</p>

<p>
Because energy prices were behind the latest rise in the PPI, many economists said a blip higher in the index would not suggest a broad trend of rising inflation pressures at the wholesale level.
</p>

<p>
In another report, the Commerce Department said U.S. retail sales rose 0.1 percent in April, shy of an expected 0.3 percent increase. Excluding auto sales, the rise was 0.4 percent.
</p>

<p>
Wednesday, the Dow index closed with a modest loss of 26 points after staging a powerful comeback from an early sell-off of more than 200 points on news of the resignation of U.S. Treasury Secretary Robert Rubin.
</p>

<p>
The good inflation news buoyed the price of bonds, and triggered a drop in their yield. The benchmark 30-year Treasury bond rose 23/32, sending the yield down to 5.77 percent from 5.83 percent at Wednesday's close.
</p>

<p>
Among the big movers, International Business Machines Corp. jumped 14 13/16 to 239 15/16 after the computer giant's chairman said the company was on track for sustained revenue growth.
</p>
]]>
</content>
<status>approved</status>
<goLiveDate>11/11/1999 00:00:00</goLiveDate>
</newsarticle>
<!-- @version $Id: //product/DSS/version/10.0.3/release/DSSJ2EEDemo/j2ee-apps/QuincyFunds/web-app/repositories/News/en_US/dowgains.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
