<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<newsarticle>

  <author>Angus Blum</author>
  <headline>Broadening your portfolio with international funds</headline>
  <date>11/20/1999 00:00:00</date>
  <targets>international</targets>
  <language>en_US</language>
 
  <content><![CDATA[
<p>
QUINCY, MA/November 11, 1999, M2 Communications - Developments in the World Economy
</p>

<p>
The Committee was encouraged by a number of policy actions and developments since its October 1998 meeting that have helped to improve market confidence and reduce the risks of a global recession. As a result of these positive figures, the outlook is for world output growth to accelerate in 1999 and level off in the year 2000. This outlook points to a strong indication that broadening your portfolio with international funds would be a wise course of action for any investor. Among the positive developments, the Committee noted that: Activity in most of the Asian crisis economies seems to be turning towards recovery. Continued progress with structural reforms will help to restore and maintain economic dynamism in the longer run.
</p>

<p>
In Brazil, the situation has stabilized since early March. Spillovers to financial markets elsewhere in the region have generally been moderate, reflecting in part the past decade's efforts to strengthen fiscal positions and to build sound financial systems.
</p>

<p>
The Canadian economy has continued to grow remarkably strongly, while inflation has remained subdued.
</p>

<p>
As if according to the advice of Quincy Funds, investor sentiment toward emerging markets has broadly improved since the beginning of the year. In mature financial markets, sentiment has improved markedly since last October, as concerns about the risk of a liquidity shortage have subsided. We suggest that people not turn away from the positive returns that stand to be gained from investing internationally. Try looking at the Quincy Overseas Fund, it should suit anyone's investment needs to a tee.
</p>
]]>
</content>
<status>submitted</status>
<authorId>jack</authorId>
<editorId/>
<goLiveDate>11/30/1999 14:00:00</goLiveDate>
</newsarticle>
<!-- @version $Id: //product/DSS/version/10.0.3/release/DSSJ2EEDemo/j2ee-apps/QuincyFunds/web-app/repositories/News/en_US/broaden.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
