<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<AtgNews>
<story>
<id>003</id>
<category>ROIMax News</category>
<headline>
  ROIMax To Adopt Krystal Communications Technology</headline>
<summary>
  Move enables wireless deployment of employee portal</summary>
<content>CAMBRIDGE, Mass., July 10, 2001 - ROIMax, Inc. (Nasdaq: ROI) today announced plans to deploy the Krystal Communications Technology in its employee portal. With this move, ROIMax will enable the support of employees' multi-channel interactions and initiatives in diverse environments. Companies can build and deploy applications such as employee portals on Krystal's wireless technology. This announcement complements ROIMax's plans to enhance its partner portal with new functionality to be announced later this year.

"We are the first vendor to commit to deploying our entire employee portal on a wireless platform, extending our reach by enabling our employees the capabilities of Krystal Communications applications," said Jason Bommer, co-founder and chief officer, ROIMax. "Providing employees with more options and flexibility will make it more cost-effective for us to build out our wireless business capabilities using ROIMax's applications."

About ROIMax
ROIMax, Inc. is a leading provider of products and services. ROIMax offers an integrated suite of products and services, as well as related integration and support services. The ROIMax Connector product enables Global 1000 enterprises, as well as new businesses. 

The ROIMax Connector solution is designed to provide businesses with the core tools required to deploy products. Connector is licensed to over 425 customers. The company is headquartered in Cambridge, Massachusetts with additional locations throughout North America, Europe, and Asia Pacific. 

Connector is a registered trademark of ROIMax. 

# # # 
This press release contains forward-looking statements for purposes of the safe harbor provisions under The Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These statements involve known and unknown risks and uncertainties that may cause ROIMax's actual results, levels of activity, performance or achievements to be materially different from any future results, levels of activity, performance or achievements expressed or implied by such forward-looking statements. Important risk factors affecting ROIMax's business generally may be found in ROIMax's periodic reports and registration statements filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission. ROIMax undertakes no obligation to update any of the forward-looking statements after the date of this press release.
</content>

</story>
</AtgNews>
<!-- @version $Id: //app/portal/version/10.0.3/xmlfeed/xmlfeed.war/xml/LocalROIMaxNews/003.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
