<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<AtgNews>
<story>
<id>010</id>
<category>Portals</category>
<headline>ATG Unveils ATG Dynamo e-Business Platform Version 5.5</headline>
<summary>Comprehensive new release strengthens support for enterprise-wide personalization, relationship management, and portal initiatives</summary>
<content>CAMBRIDGE, Mass., July 17, 2001 - ATG (Art Technology Group, Inc., Nasdaq: ARTG), provider of applications and an e-business software platform for e-commerce, relationship management, and portals, today unveiled the ATG Dynamo(r) e-Business Platform version 5.5. The latest version of ATG Dynamo includes enhancements designed to support the development and management of enterprise-wide Web initiatives with scenario-based personalization and relationship management capabilities, along with support for the new ATG Enterprise Portal Suite. General availability is scheduled for the third quarter of 2001.
The updated ATG Dynamo e-Business Platform provides enhancements for managing personalization and business rules across an enterprise, supports packaged integrations with popular enterprise applications to speed deployment, and is architected to fit into diverse IT environments. In addition, the ATG Dynamo e-Business Platform now includes support for additional relationship management models including portals and B2B initiatives.
"Since ATG was founded nearly a decade ago, our solutions have been chosen by more than 730 customers to develop applications that power the front line of their business on the Web," said Joe Chung, chairman and CTO of ATG. "This latest release of ATG Dynamo will help our customers realize greater business efficiencies and the benefits of strong relationships with integrated Web capabilities across their enterprise."
Innovative Scenario-based Personalization
ATG Dynamo e-Business Scenarios are part of the foundation of the ATG Dynamo e-Business Platform. Scenarios are business rules that are created with a visual, drag and drop interface to define interactions with customers based on their actions, profile elements, or role in an organization. They can be used in many applications, including targeting promotions, conveying alerts to members of a portal community, or for sending reminder email messages to customers who haven't returned to a Web site.
ATG Dynamo provides the ability to distribute the authorship and management of scenarios across an organization with granular security and access control - moving the creation of business rules closer to the source of expertise. In addition, new scenario server redundancy features provide the high availability required for an enterprise solution.
Integrates With Enterprise Environments
Advanced enterprise application integration (EAI) capabilities are now available for ATG Dynamo with the introduction of the Dynamo Application Integrator and Dynamo Business Integrator. These products offer packaged integrations with popular enterprise applications including PeopleSoft, SAP, Lotus Notes, and Siebel and support for B2B integration standards including cXML and RosettaNet. These EAI capabilities reduce integration costs and time to deployment.
ATG also is a pioneer in support of advanced personalization and portals across multiple application servers. The ATG Dynamo e-Business Platform includes support for the ATG Dynamo Application Server, and also will be deployable on leading third-party J2EE application servers including BEA, Hewlett-Packard, and iPlanet.
Advanced Relationship Models
New relationship management features include the ability to associate individual user profiles with sophisticated organization models. Scenarios can apply to individuals, members of departments and organizations, or people who have a specific role in an organization. These new models provide unique B2B relationship management capabilities for applications like partner relationship management portals and B2B commerce.
"The flexibility of Java-based ATG Dynamo enables its extensible platform and portfolio of applications to operate with customers' disparate systems," said Doug Kaewert, vice president, Sun Developer Network group, Sun Microsystems. "The move to application server portability helps a broader base of customers requiring the scalability, high performance, and availability of the Solaris UNIX(r) environment."
For more details about ATG Dynamo, please visit www.atg.com.
About ATG
ATG(r) (Art Technology Group, Inc.) provides applications and an e-business software platform for e-commerce, relationship management, and portals. Customers around the globe rely on ATG for the frontline applications that help build and manage mutually beneficial relationships with customers, partners, and employees. Deployed on the industry's most popular application servers, including the ATG Dynamo Application Server, ATG's integrated suite of Java(tm) applications is ideal for large-scale, rapidly-evolving, and customized Web interactions. ATG and its network of more than 300 committed technology and solution partners deliver dedicated services for client strategy, implementation and support. Together, ATG and its global alliance network provide the e-commerce and relationship management capabilities that generate loyalty, drive sales, and empower the world's most recognized companies to realize the full potential of their online initiatives.
Today, ATG has delivered e-business solutions to more than 730 companies worldwide including 3M, Abbott Laboratories, Aetna Services, Inc., Alcatel, American Airlines, ATandT, Barclays Global Investors, BMG Direct, Eastman Kodak, Ford Motor Credit, HSBC, J. Crew, Sun Microsystems, Target, and Walgreen Company. The company is headquartered in Cambridge, Massachusetts, with additional locations throughout North America, Europe, Asia, and Australia. For more information about ATG, please visit our Web site at www.atg.com.
####
(c) 2009 Art Technology Group, Inc. ATG, Art Technology Group, the Techmark, the ATG Logo, and Dynamo are registered trademarks, and Personalization Server and Scenario Server are trademarks, of Art Technology Group, Inc. All other trademarks are the property of their respective holders. NASDAQ:ARTG. Sun, Sun Microsystems, the Sun logo, iPlanet and The Network Is The Computer is a trademark or registered trademark of Sun Microsystems, Inc. in the United States and other countries.
This press release contains forward-looking statements for purposes of the safe harbor provisions under The Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These statements involve known and unknown risks and uncertainties that may cause ATG's actual results, levels of activity, performance or achievements to be materially different from any future results, levels of activity, performance or achievements expressed or implied by such forward-looking statements. Important risk factors affecting ATG's business generally may be found in their periodic reports and registration statements filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission. Risk factors related to the subject matter of this press release include the possibility that the release of the software will be delayed; the costs and risks associated with potential intellectual property infringement; that the Dynamo software will not continue to be J2EE compliant; that the software wil lnever be able to run on the application servers of third parties; that customers will move to other platforms; and that the new features in the Dynamo software suite will not work, either now or in the future. ATG undertakes no obligation to update any of the forward-looking statements after the date of this press release.</content>
</story>



</AtgNews>
<!-- @version $Id: //app/portal/version/10.0.3/xmlfeed/xmlfeed.war/xml/LocalAtgNews/010.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
