<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<AtgNews>
<story>
<id>004</id>
<category>Dynamo</category>
<headline>Sun and ATG Unveil Technology Milestones for ATG Dynamo On the Sun Platform</headline>
<summary>SunTone Program Certification and Scalability Benchmark Demonstrate Strong Technology Advantage</summary>
<content>PALO ALTO, Calif., and CAMBRIDGE, Mass., April 18, 2001 - Sun Microsystems, Inc. and ATG (Art Technology Group, Inc.) today highlighted the advantage of their combined technology with ATG's receipt of SunTone (SM) Program Certification and unprecedented benchmark results for the ATG Dynamo(TM) e-Business Platform running on Sun Enterprise(TM) 10000 servers. This announcement comes as the two companies' combined technology advantage will be further progressed with an extended technology and global marketing alliance, announced today in a separate release (See also: Sun and ATG Strengthen Relationship with Strategic Global Alliance). Working together has earned them a reputation for delivering superb e-business functionality, performance and scalability to customers in retail, financial services and emerging markets like wireless. 
Achieving Recognition for Excellence 
To provide customers with a means for identifying high-quality sources for Web services and applications, Sun has established the SunTone Certification and Branding program. As a SunTone Certified application, ATG Dynamo conforms to the program's requirements for scalability, security and manageability. 
The strength and reliability of ATG Dynamo also has been recognized by Forrester Research, which placed the ATG Dynamo Commerce Suite 5.0 first among commerce platforms in its March 2001 Commerce Platform TechRankings. 
Performance and Scalability Put to the TestTogether, ATG and Sun put their solution to the test to demonstrate the inherent scalability and strength of ATG Dynamo running on Sun systems. The scalability tests were designed as a complex, fully dynamic, personalized e-commerce Web application producing up to 582 pages per second or more than 50 million pages per day while scaling linearly as processing power was added to the deployment. This result was achieved on a realistic site using a complex combination of the features ATG offers in its ATG Dynamo Commerce Suite. The results of the "ATG Dynamo and Sun Scalability Report" show that high-performance is not compromised as advanced features and incremental processing power are added to meet the needs of a growing customer base and evolving business environment. Other performance tests show even faster results with simpler sites. 
"These results support the benefits of ATG Dynamo that we have seen in our joint customer implementations in the past," said Doug Kaewert, vice president, Sun Developer Network Group, Sun Microsystems, Inc. "ATG Dynamo, running on Sun Enterprise servers, has again demonstrated impressive scalability and high performance that businesses demand." 
Results similar to those of the laboratory simulation have been experienced in business environments by many of ATG and Sun's joint customers, including Sony Online Entertainment. Since its launch in 1997, membership on the Sony site has grown to more than 4 million users. To meet this need, ATG Dynamo has scaled on Sun servers to support as many as 150,000 concurrent users and more than 16 million hits per day. 
"Sony exemplifies the importance of the scalability ATG and Sun have achieved both in laboratory and active business environments," said Joe Chung, co-founder and CTO of ATG. "We provide the e-business foundation that enables our customers to grow their e-businesses to profitability by scaling to meet their needs every step of the way." 
With more than 650 joint customers on the Solaris(TM) Operating Environment, technology alignment is important. ATG has committed to developing customer management applications on the Java(TM) platform and embracing open, industry standards. Standards like Java(TM) technology provide for increased scalability and ease of deployment across multiple device types like wireless. With Sun's support, ATG continues to develop e-business applications for next-generation solutions, including development of wireless applications based on Sun's Java(TM) 2 platform, Micro Edition (J2ME(TM)) technology 
About ATG 
ATG (Nasdaq: ARTG) is a leading provider of customer management and e-commerce products and services. ATG offers an integrated suite of Java(TM) application server-based products and services, as well as related application development, integration and support services. The ATG Dynamo(TM) e-Business Platform enables Global 2000 enterprises, as well as new businesses using the Internet as their primary business channel, to understand, manage and build their online customer relationships and to more effectively market, sell and support their products and services over the Internet. 
With its network of more than 250 partners, ATG has delivered e-business solutions to more than 670 companies worldwide including Aetna Services, Inc., American Airlines, Blockbuster, BMG Direct, eChips, Eastman Kodak, HSBC, Herman Miller, J. Crew and Sun Microsystems. The company is headquartered in Cambridge, Massachusetts, with additional locations throughout North America, Europe, Asia and Australia. ATG can be found on the Web at www.atg.com. 
About Sun Microsystems, Inc. 
Since its inception in 1982, a singular vision -- "The Network Is The Computer(TM)" -- has propelled Sun Microsystems, Inc. (Nasdaq: SUNW), to its position as a leading provider of industrial-strength hardware, software and services that power the Internet and allow companies worldwide to take their businesses to the nth. With $19.2 billion in annual revenues, Sun can be found in more than 170 countries and on the World Wide Web at http:// www.sun.com. 
# # # 
(c) 2009 Art Technology Group, Inc. ATG, Art Technology Group, the Techmark, the ATG Logo, and Dynamo are registered trademarks, and Personalization Server and Scenario Server are trademarks, of Art Technology Group, Inc. All other trademarks are the property of their respective holders. NASDAQ:ARTG 
Sun, Sun Microsystems, the Sun Logo, Java, J2EE, Sun Enterprise, and The Network Is The Computer are trademarks or registered trademarks of Sun Microsystems, Inc. in the United States and other countries. 
This press release contains forward-looking statements for purposes of the safe harbor provisions under The Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These statements involve known and unknown risks and uncertainties that may cause ATG's actual results, levels of activity, performance or achievements to be materially different from any future results, levels of activity, performance or achievements expressed or implied by such forward-looking statements. Important risk factors affecting ATG's business generally may be found in ATG's periodic reports and registration statements filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission. Risk factors related to the subject matter of this press release include the possibility that the ATG software will not be able to perform according to the laboratory test results published in this release; that the ATG and Sun products will not remain compatible; that ATG will not remain SunTone certified; and that the risks and costs of intellectual property litigation may impair ATG's ability to supply products. ATG undertakes no obligation to update any of the forward-looking statements after the date of this press release.</content>
</story>



</AtgNews>
<!-- @version $Id: //app/portal/version/10.0.3/xmlfeed/xmlfeed.war/xml/LocalAtgNews/004.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
