<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<newsarticle>

  <author>Henry Kaiser</author>
  <headline>Quincy growth fund (QUIGG) appoints John Blake as new fund manager</headline>
  <date>11/23/1999 00:00:00</date>
  <targets>market</targets>
  <language>de_DE</language>

  <content><![CDATA[
<p>
QUINCY, MA May 13/PRNewswire/ -- The Quincy Corporation today announced the appointment of John Blake as the Manager of the Quincy Global Growth Fund (QUIGG).
</p>

<p>
Quincy CEO Robby Shaver praised the special areas of expertise the new fund
manager will bring to the Quincy.  "John Blake offers us a wealth of
expertise in the areas of distribution management, technology application,
and acquisition integration. He is a premier executive and corporate
strategist with impressive international credentials that make him
especially suited to manage the Global Growth Fund.  John also brings to us
unparalleled administrative, and government experience," Mr. Shaver said.
</p>

<p>
The Quincy Board of Directors approved the appointment effective today.  Following is a brief biography of the new Fund Manager:
</p>

<p>
John Blake-Before his appointment as President and CEO of Tyrell Corporation, Mr. Blake, age 46, served as President and COO for the company.
</p>

<p>
His experience in the artificial life form industry began in the wholesale prosthetic limb distribution business with the Tyrell Corporation.  In 1986 he worked in a senior-level sales and marketing position within Nexus Co.,
eventually becoming an EVP within that organization.  He later worked as President and COO of Replicant Corporation.  In 1994, he was hired as COO of Mr. Moto Corporation; he was appointed CEO in 1996, leading all aspects of the company's U.S. consumer products and animatronic businesses. We are lucky that he has decided to take a cut in pay and status to manage our Global Growth Fund here at Quincy.
</p>

<p>
The Quincy Corporation, through its principal operating subsidiary,  Quincy &amp; Co., Inc., is one of the nation's largest and fastest growing financial services firms, serving over 5.4 million active investor accounts through its regional telephone services centers, automated telephone services, online services and nationwide network of over 2 branches.  Total customer assets entrusted to Quincy now exceed <dollar/>4.60.
</p>
]]>
</content>
<status>approved</status>
<authorId>jack</authorId>
<editorId>jack</editorId>
<goLiveDate>11/30/1999 13:00:00</goLiveDate>
</newsarticle>
<!-- @version $Id: //product/DSS/version/10.0.3/release/DSSJ2EEDemo/j2ee-apps/QuincyFunds/web-app/repositories/News/de_DE/blakeasmanager.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
