<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<newsarticle>

  <author>Henry Kaiser</author>
  <headline>Four Quincy funds earn 5-star ratings from Morningstar</headline>
  <date>11/9/1999 00:00:00</date>
  <targets>market</targets>
  <language>de_DE</language>

  <content><![CDATA[
<p>
QUINCY, MA/November 11, 1998-Quincy is pleased to announce that four of our funds were rated five star funds by Morningstar. You might be curious to find out why our funds were given this prestigious title, and the following information should give you the answer. We warn you that upon reading this article, you may just be forced to buy into one or all of these funds, that is, if you haven't already. Take a look at what each of these funds offer and see in them what Morningstar did:
</p>

<p>
<b>The Quincy High Yield Bond Fund</b><break/>
Fund Type: Bond - Corporate<break/>
Objective: Quincy High Yield Fund seeks high current income; long-term capital appreciation is a secondary 
goal.<break/>
Strategy: The Fund invests primarily in bonds, other debt securities, and preferred stocks issued by corporations. 
Fund holdings focus primarily on obligations rated in the lower credit categories by established ratings 
services. Up to 25% of the Fund's total assets may be invested in dollar-denominated foreign debt securities, 
which are subject to special risks, such as differences in securities regulation and accounting, as well as 
currency fluctuations.
</p>

<p>
<b>The Quincy Growth Fund</b><break/>
Fund Type: Growth<break/>
Objective: Quincy Growth Fund seeks long-term capital growth, with a secondary goal of current income.<break/>
Strategy: The Fund invests primarily in larger-capitalization common stocks selected for a history of 
consistent earnings growth regardless of the business cycle. A lesser but important emphasis is placed on 
companies with accelerating earnings, revenues, and strong cash flows. The Fund may also invest in foreign 
securities which are subject to special risks, such as differences in securities and accounting regulations, 
as well as currency fluctuations.
</p>

<p>
<b>The Quincy Growth &amp; Income Fund</b><break/>
Fund Type: Growth &amp; Income<break/>
Objective: The Fund seeks high total return through a combination of capital appreciation and current income.<break/>
Strategy: The Quincy G&amp;I fund places a heavier emphasis on growth while making current income a secondary 
objective. It targets stocks that fund management believes are cheaply priced relative to their true value. 
This focus is applied to large companies poised to implement positive change, such as restructuring measures, 
new products or distribution methods, and cost reductions. This fund has the flexibility to invest in more 
medium-size companies and holds fewer stocks in more concentrated positions.
</p>

<p>
<b>The Quincy Venture Fund</b><break/>
Fund Type: Growth Sector-Technology<break/>
Objective: Quincy Venture Fund seeks long-term capital appreciation.<break/>
Strategy: The Fund invests primarily in the equity securities of companies engaged in technology-related 
industries such as computers, communications, video, electronics, oceanography, office and factory 
automation, and robotics. The Fund may invest in foreign securities, which are subject to special risks, 
such as differences in securities and accounting regulations, as well as currency fluctuations.
</p>
]]>
</content>
<status>approved</status>
<goLiveDate>11/9/1999 00:00:00</goLiveDate>
</newsarticle>
<!-- @version $Id: //product/DSS/version/10.0.3/release/DSSJ2EEDemo/j2ee-apps/QuincyFunds/web-app/repositories/News/de_DE/quincy5star.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
