<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<AtgNews>
<story>
<id>008</id>
<category>General</category>
<headline>ATG Launches Certified Professional Program For ATG Dynamo e-Business Platform</headline>
<summary>Education and advocacy promote quality and efficiency among global alliance network and customers</summary>
<content>CAMBRIDGE, Mass., July 3, 2001- ATG (Art Technology Group, Inc., Nasdaq: ARTG) today announced the launch of the ATG Certified Professional Program to promote quality and efficiency among developers using the ATG Dynamo(r) e-Business Platform. Conducted at Prometric Testing Centers around the world, certification sets professional standards that enable customers to assess the competence levels of internal IT staff and external developers from ATG and its Global Alliance Network. The certification also serves as a mark of distinction for developers designing solutions for ATG Dynamo customers. 
The Certification Program was developed in response to ATG customers who requested a base of minimum standards by which to measure ATG Dynamo developers. Through the Voice of the Customer program, an ATG Customer Advocacy program that monitors and responds to the needs of customers, ATG answered the call for a certification program for both ATG alliance developers and customers' internal development teams. The certification also acts as a quality measurement for members of the ATG Global Alliance Network, helping ATG assess its partners based on customer-centric measures, such as certification, number of successfully deployed sites, and over-all customer satisfaction. By responding to the need to qualify developers and partners, ATG is taking yet another step to help customers make the most of their ATG Dynamo e-business initiatives. 
In beta testing, 68% of candidates passed the examination and are now certified, including individuals from system integrator and ATG Global Alliance Network member Cap Gemini Ernst and Young. 
"Certification demonstrates the extensive capabilities of our integrators and developers, which is a key element in our ability to provide the highest level of consultancy to our mutual customers," said Chuck Benson, vice president at of Cap Gemini Ernst and Young "The opportunity to have some of our consultants certified on an in-demand platform like ATG Dynamo will be a differentiator for our firm during this time of intense market competition." 
The first level of certification, ATG Certified Dynamo Developer: Fundamentals and Data Access, focuses on skills and knowledge relative to the application server. In time, developers will have the opportunity to pursue additional ATG Dynamo certifications in areas that meet specific customer requirements, including e-commerce and eCRM. ATG Education Services supports the certification process with a recommended curriculum of course work, self-directed learning, and field experience. 
"Certification has been proven as a key way to maximize performance and productivity by validating that candidates can apply their knowledge and skills to their job as an application developer," said Bernard Bailey, vice president of Global Services, ATG. "Through the Certification program, we help ensure developers have the skills necessary to deliver projects on time and on budget. Maintaining our customer focus, the Certification program is yet another way ATG takes into account the full picture of our customers' needs, from technical requirements to the bottom-line." 
For more information about the ATG Certified Professional Program or other ATG education opportunities, please visit www.atg.com/services/education. 
About ATG
ATG is a leading provider of customer management and e-commerce products and services. ATG offers an integrated suite of Java(tm) application server-based products and services, as well as related application development, integration and support services. The ATG Dynamo(r) e-Business Platform enables Global 2000 enterprises, as well as new businesses using the Internet as their primary business channel, to understand, manage and build their online customer relationships and to more effectively market, sell and support their products and services over the Internet. 
With its network of more than 300 partners, ATG has delivered e-business solutions to over 730 companies worldwide including 3M, Aetna Services, Inc., American Airlines, BMG Direct, eChips, Eastman Kodak, HSBC, Herman Miller, J. Crew and Sun Microsystems. The company is headquartered in Cambridge, Massachusetts with additional locations throughout North America, Europe, Asia and Australia. www.atg.com. 
### 
(c)2009 Art Technology Group, Inc. ATG, Art Technology Group, the Techmark, the ATG Logo, and Dynamo are registered trademarks, and Personalization Server and Scenario Server are trademarks, of Art Technology Group, Inc. All other trademarks are the property of their respective holders. NASDAQ:ARTG 
This press release contains forward-looking statements for purposes of the safe harbor provisions under The Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These statements involve known and unknown risks and uncertainties that may cause ATG's actual results, levels of activity, performance or achievements to be materially different from any future results, levels of activity, performance or achievements expressed or implied by such forward-looking statements. Important risk factors affecting ATG's business generally may be found in their periodic reports and registration statements filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission. Risk factors related to the subject matter of this press release include the possibility that certification will not adequately prepare partners or customers to provide the highest level of services; that the certification program will be continued or constantly updated; that partners will engage in the certification process; or that certification will result in the design or deployment or better quality Web sites for end users. ATG undertakes no obligation to update any of the forward-looking statements after the date of this press release.</content>
</story>



</AtgNews>
<!-- @version $Id: //app/portal/version/10.0.3/xmlfeed/xmlfeed.war/xml/LocalAtgNews/008.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
