<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<AtgNews>
<story>
<id>009</id>
<category>Portals</category>
<headline>ATG Launches Gear Network, Enhances ATG Enterprise Portal Suite with Components from Partner Community</headline>
<summary>Comprehensive building blocks offer full functionality to portal customers</summary>
<content>CAMBRIDGE, Mass., July 17, 2001 - ATG (Art Technology Group, Inc., Nasdaq: ARTG) today announced the formation of the ATG Dynamo(r) Gear Network. The network of partner-developed solutions is designed to enhance the functionality of the new ATG Enterprise Portal Suite through an extensive set of portal building blocks, called gears, which will provide customers with a robust and expanding feature set to build portals for customers, partners, and employees.
ATG partners will provide integrated gears to deliver functionality in several application categories. In addition to ATG's framework platform and foundation gears for enterprise application integration, the Gear Network enables third-party developers to deliver best-in-class component software features. The Network allows partners with technology that works within an open Java environment to plug their own solution into ATG's portal offering.
"Portals have matured into a critical enterprise-wide relationship management tool," said Jeet Singh, co-founder and CEO of ATG. "Businesses require an environment that provides a simple, intuitive platform for fast implementation and the flexibility to adapt to dynamic business needs. The open, Java-based architecture of the ATG Dynamo e-Business Platform makes it easy for our partners to configure and integrate valuable components without a heavy investment of time or financial resources."
The ATG Gear Network consists of more than 20 leading vendors across technology and solution domains, including:
* Business Intelligence - NetGenesis 
* Content Management - Documentum, Escenic, Interwoven, and Mediasurface 
* Content Aggregation - Information Architects 
* Content Syndication - Screaming Media, YellowBrix, Newsedge, and iMediation 
* Web Services - Patkai 
* Collaboration - Message Machines 
* Search - AltaVista and Verity 
* Enterprise Systems - TIBCO, YOUcentric 
* Security - Netegrity 
* Systems Integrators - Appian, Fort Point Partners, ISL Consulting, McFadyen Consulting, and Novo 
* Wireless/Mobile - Volantis 
"Through the ATG Gear Network, we are able to provide ATG customers seamless delivery of our content solutions within their portal framework to improve communications while reducing costs of information distribution," said Kevin Clark, CEO of ScreamingMedia. "We have built gears that directly integrate our technology into the ATG Enterprise Portal Suite, creating a more robust experience for end-users."
The ATG Dynamo Gear Network enables partners to develop and market their products as a Dynamo Gear and expands joint business opportunities. The ATG Dynamo product suite's open, component-based architecture lets partners easily create gears that can be packaged and reused across applications such as portals, bringing additional value to ATG's partnerships.
"Verity's professional services team worked jointly with ATG on many customer deployments for several years," says Mike Mooney, vice president of business development at Verity. "As the leader in search and content classification solutions, we are pleased to formalize our partnership with ATG through the development of a gear. This new partnership will expand support of the integration of Verity's business portal infrastructure software with ATG's e-business application."
Most of the partner gears are currently under development and will be available from the Gear Network on atg.com later in Q3 2001. ATG is actively recruiting partners for the Gear Network through the ATG Gear Alliance Program. For more information, visit www.atg.com.
About ATG
ATG(r) (Art Technology Group, Inc.) provides applications and an e-business software platform for e-commerce, relationship management, and portals. Customers around the globe rely on ATG for the frontline applications that help build and manage mutually beneficial relationships with customers, partners, and employees. Deployed on the industry's most popular application servers, including the ATG Dynamo Application Server, ATG's integrated suite of Java(tm) applications is ideal for large-scale, rapidly evolving, and customized Web interactions. ATG and its network of more than 300 committed technology and solution partners deliver dedicated services for client strategy, implementation and support. Together, ATG and its global alliance network provide the e-commerce and relationship management capabilities that generate loyalty, drive sales, and empower the world's most recognized companies to realize the full potential of their online initiatives.
Today, ATG has delivered e-business solutions to more than 730 companies worldwide including 3M, Abbott Laboratories, Aetna Services, Inc., Alcatel, American Airlines, ATandT, Barclays Global Investors, BMG Direct, Eastman Kodak, Ford Motor Credit, HSBC, J. Crew, Sun Microsystems, and Walgreen Company. The company is headquartered in Cambridge, Massachusetts, with additional locations throughout North America, Europe, and Asia. For more information about ATG, please visit our Web site at www.atg.com.
####
(c) 2009 Art Technology Group, Inc. ATG, Art Technology Group, the Techmark, the ATG Logo, and Dynamo are registered trademarks, and Personalization Server and Scenario Server are trademarks, of Art Technology Group, Inc. All other trademarks are the property of their respective holders. NASDAQ:ARTG
This press release contains forward-looking statements for purposes of the safe harbor provisions under The Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These statements involve known and unknown risks and uncertainties that may cause ATG's actual results, levels of activity, performance or achievements to be materially different from any future results, levels of activity, performance or achievements expressed or implied by such forward-looking statements. Important risk factors affecting ATG's business generally may be found in their periodic reports and registration statements filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission. Risk factors related to the subject matter of this press release include the possibility that no gears will be developed or deployed; that few partners will participate in the Gear Network; that gears will not be or remain compatible; that Java(tm) will cease to be the standard for development; and the costs and risks associated with intellectual property violations. ATG undertakes no obligation to update any of the forward-looking statements after the date of this press release.</content>
</story>



</AtgNews>
<!-- @version $Id: //app/portal/version/10.0.3/xmlfeed/xmlfeed.war/xml/LocalAtgNews/009.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
