<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<AtgNews>


<story>
<id>001</id>
<category>
Dynamo
</category>

<headline>
Art Technology Group Ships First Java(tm) 2 Platform, Enterprise Edition (J2EE(tm)) Certified Customer Management Solution
</headline>

<summary>
ATG Dynamo 5 Platform Featuring Industry's Only eBusiness Scenario-based Personalization Technology
</summary>

<content>
CAMBRIDGE, Mass., -September 7, 2000 - Art Technology Group, Inc. ("ATG") (Nasdaq: ARTG) today announced the general availability of ATG Dynamo(r) 5 e-Business Platform, the industry's first shipping, fully certified Java(tm) 2 Platform, Enterprise Edition (J2EE(tm)) customer management solution. Building on its tradition of technology innovation, ATG brings to market a powerful new way to manage personalized customer interactions across the enterprise. ATG Dynamo 5 helps enable e-businesses to achieve the goal of any relationship strategy: to convert browsers into customers and turn interest into loyalty. 
The ATG Dynamo 5 e-Business Platform delivers three key components that are critical to e-business success: scenario-based personalization -- an industry first and the cornerstone of the ATG Dynamo 5 solution; a deployment-ready and customizable B-to-B and B-to-C commerce application; and a highly scalable, fully J2EE compliant application server critical for evolving applications. ATG's implementation of the full J2EE standard in the Dynamo 5 platform ensures that customers and partners are provided with an open and highly flexible architecture that allows them to keep pace with their changing business needs. 
"ATG is committed to providing a fully integrated solution entirely written on the Java platform for businesses that want to improve their e-business efforts," said Joseph Chung, ATG co-founder and chief technology officer. "With the delivery of ATG Dynamo 5, not only are we one of the first shipping application servers to receive the J2EE- compatible brand certification, but we are also bringing a full suite of 100 percent Java technology-based applications that significantly advance the delivery of a complete customer management solution. With ATG Dynamo 5, we're providing full featured applications that speed delivery of commerce and optimize personalization with breakthrough scenario-driven technology, while retaining the advantage of being fully customizable and extensible." 
"As the first customer management platform provider to be J2EE certified, ATG is taking a leadership role in the enterprise e-business economy," said Richard Green, Vice President Java Software Development, Software Systems Group at Sun Microsystems, Inc. "We are pleased to have an e-commerce powerhouse and Java technology pioneer like ATG among the family of J2EE technology-compatible application servers. ATG Dynamo's J2EE specification-compatible platform, combined with its 100% Java technology-based customer management applications, are important to advanced enterprise e-businesses." With Dynamo 5, ATG is a pioneer in real-time scenario-driven personalization of the online customer experience - from customer acquisition and behavior to retention and loyalty - to increase lifetime customer value. Dynamo 5's scenario-driven approach to rules-based personalization uses real-time profiling and user segmentation to create targeted interactions across channels including wireless devices. Scenarios allow business managers to define the goals of an online customer relationship and build a personalization scenario that drives future behavior and interactions to achieve them. ATG Dynamo 5 delivers the out-of-box capabilities that accelerate time to launch, as well as the ability to rapidly re-launch that is critical for effective B-to-B and B-to-C commerce. Dynamo 5 will allow businesses to rapidly develop and deploy online initiatives as a result of its full J2EE platform compliance and mobile device compatibility through WAP and WML standards. 
"ATG Dynamo 5, especially with the scenario and personalization technology, provides a rich environment for our clients to achieve many of their e-Business strategic goals that have been difficult to reach," said Steve Pratt, Deloitte Consulting's Global Customer Relationship Management Practice Leader. "ATG Dynamo 5 adds the needed feature sets to create a strong relationship between our clients and their customers. ATG has also made it an easy technology decision with J2EE platform certification, open architecture and scalability." 
"ATG Dynamo's open architecture and scalability has enabled Esselte, one of the world's leading manufacturers of office supplies, to meet its global business needs," said David Taylor, VP, Global Web Marketing and Technology at Esselte. "The personalization and scenario-driven technology of ATG Dynamo 5 is key to meeting the future needs of our customers whose interests span our many brands and product categories on a worldwide basis." ATG has over 200 early access participants performing beta testing and developing e-business applications using ATG Dynamo 5 e-Business Platform. ATG Dynamo supports J2EE specifications, including Enterprise JavaBeans(tm) (EJB(tm)), JavaServer Pages(tm) (JSP(tm)), Servlets, Java Messaging Service (JMS), and the Java TransactionAPI (JTA), defining the standard platform for today's e-commerce applications. For more information visit ATG at www.atg.com.
About ATG
Art Technology Group, Inc. is a leading provider of customer relationship management and electronic commerce products and services. ATG offers an integrated suite of Java application server-based products and services, as well as related application development, integration, and support services. The ATG Dynamo e-Business Platform enables Global 1000 enterprises, as well as new businesses using the Internet as their primary business channel, to understand, manage, and build their online customer relationships and to more effectively market, sell, and support their products and services over the Internet. 
The ATG Dynamo solution is designed to provide businesses with the core platform and software tools required to develop and deploy personalized, scalable, and reliable e-commerce Web sites. Dynamo is licensed to over 425 customers including 3M, BabyCenter, BMG Direct, Eastman Kodak, Informix, J. Crew, Network, Solutions, Sun Microsystems, and TheStreet.com. The company is headquartered in Cambridge, Massachusetts with additional locations throughout North America, Europe, and Asia Pacific. 
Dynamo is a registered trademark of Art Technology Group. Sun, Sun Microsystems, the Sun Logo, Java, J2EE, Enterprise JavaBeans, EJB, JavaServer Pagers and JSP are trademarks or registered trademarks in the United States and all other countries. 
# # # 
This press release contains forward-looking statements for purposes of the safe harbor provisions under The Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These statements involve known and unknown risks and uncertainties that may cause ATG's actual results, levels of activity, performance or achievements to be materially different from any future results, levels of activity, performance or achievements expressed or implied by such forward-looking statements. Important risk factors affecting ATG's business generally may be found in ATG's periodic reports and registration statements filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission. Risk factors related to the subject matter of this press release include the possibility the ATG Dynamo software will not remain J2EE-certified; that the software will not function properly in conjunction with partners' or customers' software or services, either now or in the future; unrealistic customer and strategic partner expectations; and the costs and risks associated with intellectual property infringement and litigation. ATG undertakes no obligation to update any of the forward-looking statements after the date of this press release.
</content>

</story>
</AtgNews>
<!-- @version $Id: //app/portal/version/10.0.3/xmlfeed/xmlfeed.war/xml/LocalAtgNews/001.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
