<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<AtgNews>
<story>
<id>005</id>
<category>General</category>
<headline>ATG and HP Announce Alliance to Provide e-Business and e-CRM Offering on HP-UX Platform</headline>
<summary>ATG and Hewlett-Packard to co-sell combined offering and participate in global joint marketing activities</summary>
<content>CAMBRIDGE, Mass. and PALO ALTO, Calif.  April 12, 2001  ATG (Art Technology Group, Inc., Nasdaq: ARTG) and Hewlett-Packard Company (NYSE: HWP) today announced an alliance to bring customers a highly available offering for e-business and customer management on the HP-UX platform. ATG and HP are working together to co-sell the combined offering and participate in global joint marketing activities. 
The alliance outlines the integration of HP-UX 11.0 with the ATG Dynamo(r) e-Business Platform. ATG and HP will work together to assist joint customers with the integration of the ATG Dynamo(r) e-Business Platform with HP software including HP OpenView, HP Process Manager and HP Web QoS. In addition, the companies will continue to expand their offerings through ATG's support of the HP Netaction software suite. 
"This alliance allows customers dedicated to HP to capitalize on the functionality of ATG Dynamo while maintaining the integrity and stability of their current environment," said Joe Chung, ATG co-founder and CTO. "HP's Internet infrastructure helps give businesses the dependability they need to maximize their ATG Dynamo capabilities and quickly realize a return on their technology investments." 
"The product offerings coming from ATG have created an intense push for its technology and services, which we are pleased to make available to customers dedicated to the HP platform," said Nigel Ball, vice president and general managerfor HP e-Services Partner Division. "Our joint sales, marketing and technology initiatives with ATG help ensure that HP customers will continue to have access to one of the most manageable and sustainable e-businesses offerings on the market." 
"FlipDog.com wanted zero downtime through an ATG-compatible solution that could quickly scale to handle our rapid growth," said Mark Simonsen, president and CEO of FlipDog.com. "HP's infrastructure, combined with the functionality of the ATG Dynamo solution, enables us to deliver products to market quickly on a scalable, high-performance platform and stay one step ahead of our customers' demands." 
Large systems integrators and mutual channel partners will assist with the delivery of customer focused e-business solutions. 
Joint marketing activities include the launch of a European ATG and HP campaign called "Making e-Business Mobile and Personal," which focuses on multi-channel and online customer management for the financial services, retail and telecommunications markets. HP will also be a platinum sponsor at the ATG Open 2001. 
About HP 
Hewlett-Packard Company -- a leading global provider of computing and imaging solutions and services -- is focused on making technology and its benefits accessible to individuals and businesses through simple appliances, useful e-services and solutions for an Internet infrastructure that's always on. 
HP had total revenue from continuing operations of $48.8 billion in its 2000 fiscal year. Information about HP and its products can be found on the World Wide Web at http://www.hp.com. 
About ATG 
ATG is a leading provider of online customer relationship management and electronic commerce products and services. ATG offers an integrated suite of Java application server-based products and services, as well as related application development, integration and support services. The ATG Dynamo e-Business Platform enables Global 2000 enterprises, as well as new businesses using the Internet as their primary business channel, to understand, manage and build their online customer relationships and to more effectively market, sell and support their products and services over the Internet. 
With its network of more than 250 partners, ATG has delivered e-business solutions to over 670 companies worldwide including 3M, Aetna Services, Inc., American Airlines, Blockbuster, BMG Direct, eChips, Eastman Kodak, HSBC, Herman Miller and J. Crew. The company is headquartered in Cambridge, Massachusetts with additional locations throughout North America, Europe, Asia and Australia. 
# # # 
ATG, Art Technology Group, the Techmark, the ATG Logo, and Dynamo are registered trademarks, and Personalization Server and Scenario Server are trademarks, of Art Technology Group, Inc. HP-UX Release 10.20 and later and HP-UX Release 11.00 and later (in both 32- and 64-bit configurations) on all HP 9000 computers are Open Group UNIX 95 branded products. UNIX is a registered trademark of the Open Group. All other trademarks are the property of their respective holders. NASDAQ:ARTG 
This press release contains forward-looking statements for purposes of the safe harbor provisions under The Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These statements involve known and unknown risks and uncertainties that may cause the two companies' actual results, levels of activity, performance or achievements to be materially different from any future results, levels of activity, performance or achievements expressed or implied by such forward-looking statements. Important risk factors affecting the two companies' business generally may be found in their respective periodic reports and registration statements filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission. Risk factors related to the subject matter of this press release include the possibility that the ATG and HP product deployment will not significantly enhance the user's Internet experience or be able to accommodate increased user volume; that customers will not experience reliability in their web site deployments; that customers will not be able to increase the speed of their deployments; that the products of the two companies will not remain integrated or function together, either now or in the future; and that the two companies will not continue to add common customers. ATG and HP undertake no obligation to update any of the forward-looking statements after the date of this press release.</content>
</story>



</AtgNews>
<!-- @version $Id: //app/portal/version/10.0.3/xmlfeed/xmlfeed.war/xml/LocalAtgNews/005.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
