<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<AtgNews>
<story>
<id>006</id>
<category>General</category>
<headline>ATG Arms Alliance Network with New Programs to Increase Efficiency and Drive Customer Satisfaction</headline>
<summary>ATG Global Alliance Network Exceeds 2000 Goals with 5,000 Consultants Trained and 80 Percent of Revenues Influenced By Partners; New Alliance Services in 2001</summary>
<content>NEW ORLEANS, Louisiana - April 17, 2001 - ATG (Art Technology Group, Inc., Nasdaq: ARTG), a provider of customer management and e-commerce applications, today announced at its annual user conference that the ATG Global Alliance Network (formerly the Dynamo Partner Program) exceeded its goals for 2000 and is expanding services and support for its 250+ partners. The new programs, including enhanced alliance-centric training, Dynamo(r) software implementation services and the company's first certification program for individual developers, demonstrate ATG's commitment to helping its partners build solutions that increase customer satisfaction. 
In the first quarter of 2000, ATG launched an extensive partner program and identified aggressive goals for its alliances. One year later, ATG has exceeded these goals, demonstrating the company's emphasis on success with its partners: 
 ATG revenue from alliances in 2000 - Goal: 75%; Actual: 80% 
 ATG Dynamo-trained engineers in 2000 - Goal: 2,000; Actual: 5,000 
"In this competitive market, companies require strong allies to win," said Ian Dwyer, ATG's vice president, global alliance sales. "In 2000, we formed 200 new alliances, conducted extensive training, and conquered significant ground, but in 2001, we are focusing our efforts. We are deepening our alliances to extend our sales reach and improve our success penetrating key accounts." 
Taking measures to ensure it continues to empower partners with quality services and tools, ATG has extended its Global Alliance Network to deliver more complete solutions. ATG now provides partners with a Dynamo(r) software certification program for engineers, services packages and tailored training support. ATG has also increased its focus on global solutions integrators, major platform vendors and complementary software vendors to more efficiently serve its Global 2000 client base. ATG has added two new programs to address specific needs of these vendors. 
The Global Alliance Network now includes the following programs: 
 New: ATG Service Providers - Application service providers (ASPs) and others who provide a combination of hosting, management, and support services for ATG Dynamo software applications 
 New: ATG Dynamo Software ISV - Independent software vendors who will license ATG Dynamo software as a platform for their applications 
 ATG Solution Providers - Regional, national and global systems integrators and business consultancies 
 ATG Complementary Software Vendors (CSV) - Previously the Technology Partner program; consists of software vendors that enhance the capabilities of ATG Dynamo software to provide a complete solution for customers 
 ATG Strategic Platform Alliances - Major hardware vendor platforms 
Recognizing that a large portion of its revenue is driven in conjunction with partners and that customer retention is essential in a customer economy, ATG is committed to working with its partners to support quality deployments. To ensure that high standards of consulting, technical support and management are achieved, ATG will extend its regular customer surveys to gauge customer satisfaction with partners and channel-driven projects. 
About ATG 
ATG is a leading provider of customer management and e-commerce products and services. ATG offers an integrated suite of Java application server-based products and services, as well as related application development, integration and support services. The ATG Dynamo(r) e-Business Platform enables Global 2000 enterprises, as well as new businesses using the Internet as their primary business channel, to understand, manage and build their online customer relationships and to more effectively market, sell and support their products and services over the Internet. 
With its network of more than 250 solution partners, ATG has delivered e-business solutions to over 670 companies worldwide including 3M, Aetna Services, Inc., American Airlines, Blockbuster, BMG Direct, eChips, Eastman Kodak, HSBC, Herman Miller, J. Crew, and Sun Microsystems. The company is headquartered in Cambridge, Massachusetts with additional locations throughout North America, Europe, Asia and Australia. 
www.atg.com 
# # # 
Dynamo, ATG, and Art Technology Group are registered trademarks of Art Technology Group, Inc. All other product names, service marks, and trademarks mentioned herein are trademarks of their respective owners. 
This press release contains forward-looking statements for purposes of the safe harbor provisions under The Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These statements involve known and unknown risks and uncertainties that may cause ATG's actual results, levels of activity, performance, or achievements to be materially different from any future results, levels of activity, performance, or achievements expressed or implied by such forward-looking statements. Important risk factors affecting ATG business generally may be found in periodic ATG reports and registration statements filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission. Risk factors specific to the subject matter of this release include the possibility that not all programs will continue to be offered; that the structure of the programs will change; that the percentage of revenue attributable to partner influence will change; and that the programs identified above will not achieve their stated goals. ATG undertakes no obligation to update any of the forward-looking statements after the date of this press release.</content>
</story>



</AtgNews>
<!-- @version $Id: //app/portal/version/10.0.3/xmlfeed/xmlfeed.war/xml/LocalAtgNews/006.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
