<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<AtgNews>
<story>
<id>007</id>
<category>General</category>
<headline>ATG Brings Customer Management and e-Commerce Applications to Government Sector</headline>
<summary>ATG Forms Strategic Relationship with GTSI(r) to Bring ATG Dynamo to e-Government; Also Forms Government Solutions Group</summary>
<content>CAMBRIDGE, Mass., April 24, 2001 - ATG (Art Technology Group, Nasdaq: (ARTG) today announced a one-year exclusive agreement with GTSI(r) Corp. (Nasdaq:GTSI) to distribute ATGs Dynamo(r) e-Business Platform to U.S. federal and local government through GTSI's NIH ECS (National Institutes of Health Electronic Computer Store) and NASA SEWP (Scientific and Engineering Worksed tons Procurement) contracts and a number of other BPAs (Blanket Purchase Agreements). ATG also announced the formation of its Government Solutions group to address the specific requirements of e-government initiatives. 
"At GTSI, we want our customers to have the tools they need to make the best use of information," said Dendy Young, GTSI chairman and CEO. "ATG Dynamo can help our government customers enhance their online programs and web offerings and personalize the experience for each customer, partner or employee. This will be of great value in offering first-rate customer service to the American people."
ATG is steadily raising its profile in the sector. It was a sponsor for Federal Computer Week's Government CIO Summit in November of 2000. Co-founder and CTO Joe Chung addressed the CIO Council Committee for E-Government, in Washington D.C. on March 19th.
"As we enter the government sector, we are experiencing significant momentum, demonstrated by ATG's relationships with the leaders in the sector," said Paul Shorthose, ATG President and COO. "The impact of the Web on how government agencies serve their constituents will be dramatic. Taxpayers will demand the best of service and convenience. ATG has built a strong Government Solutions team, to work in conjunction with an impressive list of partners, to make that happen."
About GTSI
GTSI is the most experienced business to government (B2G) marketer of information technology solutions to Federal, state and local government customers worldwide. Profitable and growing, GTSI is headquartered in the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area and offers access to 250,000 products from more than 1,300 manufacturers. GTSI also offers customers multiple integration services to meet their needs. See http://www.gtsi.com
About ATG
ATG is a leading provider of customer management and e-commerce products and services. ATG offers an integrated suite of Java(tm)application server-based products and services, as well as related application development, integration and support services. The ATG Dynamo(r) e-Business Platform enables Global 2000 enterprises, as well as new businesses using the Internet as their primary business channel, to understand, manage and build their online customer relationships and to more effectively market, sell and support their products and services over the Internet.
With its network of more than 250 partners, ATG has delivered e-business solutions to over 670 companies worldwide including 3M, Aetna Services, Inc., American Airlines, Blockbuster, BMG Direct, eChips, Eastman Kodak, HSBC, Herman Miller, J. Crew and Sun Microsystems. The company is headquartered in Cambridge, Massachusetts with additional locations throughout North America, Europe, Asia and Australia. www.atg.com.
# # # 
Dynamo, ATG and Art Technology Group are registered trademarks of Art Technology Group, Inc. GTSI Reg. U.S. Pat. and Tm Off. All other product names, service marks, and trademarks mentioned herein are trademarks of their respective owners.
This press release contains forward-looking statements for purposes of the safe harbor provisions under The Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These statements involve known and unknown risks and uncertainties that may cause ATG's actual results, levels of activity, performance or achievements to be materially different from any future results, levels of activity, performance or achievements expressed or implied by such forward-looking statements. Important risk factors affecting ATG's business generally may be found in ATG's periodic reports and registration statements filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission. Risk factors related to the subject matter of this press release include the possibility that ATG product deployments will not significantly enhance the user's internet experience; the ATG products may not accommodate user volumes; the need to adapt to rapid changes so products do not become obsolete; the possibility of errors in ATG's software products; the costs and risks associated with intellectual property infringement and litigation; the possibility that the agreement with GTSI will end.. ATG undertakes no obligation to update any of the forward-looking statements after the date of this press release.</content>
</story>



</AtgNews>
<!-- @version $Id: //app/portal/version/10.0.3/xmlfeed/xmlfeed.war/xml/LocalAtgNews/007.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
