<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<newsarticle>

  <author>Sampson Lyrret</author>
  <headline>Take advantage of all 1999 tax changes</headline>
  <date>11/16/1999 00:00:00</date>
  <targets>tax</targets>
  <language>de_DE</language>
 
  <content><![CDATA[
<p>
WASHINGTON (CBS.MW) -- The good news for U.S. investors is their taxes are falling. The bad news is their taxes -- and their investments -- are getting much more complicated.
</p>

<p>
As the end of the year approaches, most taxpayers are just beginning to
look at the details of the 1996 tax bill, which includes many goodies for
middle-class Americans who save for retirement, education or their
children.
</p>

<p>
It will cut net taxes by <dollar/>95 billion over the next five years, and <dollar/>275 billion over 10 years. Key changes include:
</p>

<p>
<ul type="square">
<li>A <dollar/>500 per child tax credit;</li>
<li>A gradual increase in the threshold for estate taxes to <dollar/>1 million;</li>
<li>Various education incentives, including a tax credit of up to <dollar/>1,500 for two years of college and a new education savings account;</li>
<li>New individual retirement accounts, or IRAs. See Full story</li>
</ul>
</p>

<p>
However, the biggest change will help the owners of stocks, bonds and other
productive property. Congress agreed to lower the capital gains tax rates
as part of the Balanced Budget Act. To balance the budget, Congress was
counting on massive redemptions of capital gains in the next few years. So
far, however, there is little evidence of a massive sell-off.
</p>

<p>
"I have not seen or heard of any great rush to the market to sell," said
Larry Rabun, national director of estate planning services at Deloitte &amp;
Touche. "You're in the market for the long haul ... Don't run out and start
selling securities because you're scared or because of tax reasons."
</p>

<p>
Taking stock
</p>

<p>
Regardless of the ultimate impact on the economy, the new tax law is giving
high income taxpayers a good reason to re-evaluate their whole financial
strategy.
</p>

<p>
Tax dodges are possible because capital gains get tax-preferred treatment
over other forms of capital income like interest payments, dividends or
rent, which are taxed as ordinary income at rates as high as 39.6
percent. By contrast, capital gains on investments held at least 18 months
will be taxed at a maximum of 20 percent. (See chart in left margin.)
</p>

<p>
Stephen Corrick, a tax partner with Arthur Anderson, said the new law provides opportunities for "tax-rate arbitrage." His firm advises investors to consider the tax consequences of all their investments and to make changes based on their own risk-reward profile.
</p>

<p>
Some tax-saving tactics suggested by Arthur Anderson include:
</p>

<p>
<ul type="square">
<li>Shift growth investments (with possible capital gains) out of qualified retirement programs and replace them with lower-risk investments that pay dividends or interest. Retirement plans don't give investors payouts in capital gains, so the new rates don't help.</li>
<li>Asking employers to put some compensation income in stock options that can be sold at a gain.</li>
<li>Time stock sales to come just before dividends are paid to take advantage of the boost in price without getting saddled with the ordinary income from the dividend.</li>
<li>Take early distributions from qualified plans and put the proceeds into growth investments.</li>
</ul>
</p>

<p>
Risky business
</p>

<p>
Many of these tactics involve switching into higher risk investments, which
are more likely to realize capital gains. Traditionally, blue-chip stocks,
particularly utilities that pay regular dividends, have been some of the
safest investments for people who want a steady stream of income.
</p>

<p>
The new law favors investments in higher risk companies over the old
reliables, continuing a long-term trend away from dividends and toward
capital gains.
</p>

<p>
"There is an added incentive to invest in stocks and other assets that are
expected to appreciate because when you cash out your gains, the tax bite
may be less," says accounting firm KPMG.   
</p>

<p>
Many corporations have been under pressure for some time to "increase
shareholder value," which is code for rewarding investors in capital gains
rather than in dividends. For years, many corporations have bought their
own stock with their retained earnings, rather than passing them on as
dividends.
</p>

<p>
New pitfalls?
</p>

<p>
But critics of the new law and some financial planners say the new rates
could lead to new tax shelters and schemes that will simply shift money
from heavily taxed investments to lower taxed investments, with no net gain
to the economy.
</p>

<p>
"Despite what some politicians and pundits would have us believe, the
impact of this legislation on the economy is likely to be small," says
accounting and financial planning firm Arthur Anderson.
</p>

<p>
"New capital gains tax loopholes and corporate tax breaks will inspire lawyers and accountants to invent a new generation of tax avoidance schemes for their clients," says the liberal nonprofit organization Citizens for Tax Justice. "These are likely to spur tax-motivated, economically foolish investments at the expense of good ones."
</p>]]>
</content>
<status>claimed</status>
<authorId>jack</authorId>
<editorId>jack</editorId>
<goLiveDate>11/16/1999 00:00:00</goLiveDate>
</newsarticle>
<!-- @version $Id: //product/DSS/version/10.0.3/release/DSSJ2EEDemo/j2ee-apps/QuincyFunds/web-app/repositories/News/de_DE/advantage.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
