<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<newsarticle>

  <author>Janos Starker</author>
  <headline>Growth vs. Value Investing</headline>
  <date>11/17/1999 00:00:00</date>
  <targets>growth</targets>
  <language>de_DE</language>
 
  <content><![CDATA[
<p>
QUINCY, MA/November 11, 1998-When building an equity portfolio, you can choose among thousands of stocks. You can also choose between two different investment styles: value or growth. 
</p>

<p>
<ul type="square">
<li>Value investors seek out stocks that are currently undervalued by the market.</li>
<li>Growth investors focus on stocks of companies that are experiencing rapid growth in earnings, sales or return on equity.</li>
</ul>
</p>

<p>
In recent years, value investing has taken a back seat to growth, but it probably won't always be this way. "Over time, you sometimes see value in favor and sometimes see growth in favor," says Charles Schwab Vice President Mark Riepe. "You can't predict which will come out ahead in the short term. That's an argument for diversifying across the two styles. But there's a strong argument for a value tilt to a portfolio--historically, over the long term, value stock indexes have tended to outperform growth stock indexes, particularly after adjusting for risk." Investors who want to rebalance their portfolio toward value can follow three key steps:
</p>

<p>
<ol>
<li>Screen for statistically undervalued stocks.</li>
<li>Screen further for firms whose stock is depressed due to public misperception or overreaction.</li>
<li>Invest in those few situations where a catalyst is likely to emerge to unlock value and potentially boost the stock price.</li>
</ol>
</p>

<p>
Undervalued stocks
</p>

<p>
Start by looking for stocks or sectors that are selling at "cheap" valuations, both relative to their peers and their own histories. The classic trio of valuation yardsticks is made up of the price-to-book ratio (P/B), price-to-earnings ratio (P/E) and dividend yield. Value investors generally look for low P/B and P/E ratios and high dividend yields as indicators that a stock is trading at historically cheap valuations. If a stock is trading at a P/E of 10, for instance, when the average stock in its industry group is trading at a P/E of 14, the stock may be undervalued. If the stock's historical P/E has averaged well above 10, this is further confirmation that the stock may be currently out of favor. The Value Line Investment Survey, a weekly stock analysis service, offers detailed information on historical P/Es, as well as P/Bs and yields. A 10-week, <dollar/>55 trial subscription includes a reference binder containing the 13 most recent issues, with detailed, single-page reports covering 1,700 stocks. Value Line is also available in many libraries' business sections.
</p>

<p>
Misperception and overreaction
</p>

<p>
The next step is to ask, "Why is this stock so cheap?" Many cheap-looking stocks are inexpensive for good reason, like a flawed business plan, inferior management or excessive debt. The art and science of value investing is to find out-of-favor companies and sectors where prospects exceed expectations. Famed value investor David Dreman offers the bank crisis of 1990 as an example. During the crisis, according to Dreman, the average bank stock fell more than 50 percent. Some stocks were down 70 percent or more. Amidst this carnage, the stocks of relatively solid banks were sold along with the marginal performers. But some banks, says Dreman, had already written off many of their bad loans and were unduly punished by the panic. After the crisis, many of these stronger institutions prospered. The moral is that the stronger companies in struggling or battered sectors are more likely to survive a shakeout and may emerge with greater market share as the industry's weaker firms go out of business. To find stronger companies, you'll need to do some homework. Delve into corporate balance sheets and look for reasonable debt levels. Also, gather research reports (one excellent resource is Multex Investor Network), ask questions of the company's investor relations department and read industry trade magazines and journals.
</p>

<p>
Catalyst that unlocks value
</p>

<p>
Because inexpensive stock can stay inexpensive for a long, long time, value investors typically search for a catalyst--a company development or news event that could change the company's fundamentals and/or investor perceptions in a positive and lasting manner. A catalyst may be a corporate restructuring, a merger, a change in management, the sale of a major asset, a spin-off or winning a major lawsuit. All have the potential to unlock hidden value. A corporate stock buyback, a wave of insider buying or an accumulation of shares by an outside investor can also improve investor perceptions. You can look for patterns of share purchases by reading 10-K and 10-Q forms that firms issue quarterly. Specialty newsletters such as Vickers Weekly Insider also track insider buying.
</p>

<p>
Value investing in a strong market
</p>

<p>
Value investing is not easy, especially in a bull market. The higher that average valuations (such as P/E and P/B) climb, the more difficult it becomes to find stocks that are truly inexpensive. Also, the few remaining firms that look inexpensive are more and more likely to be troubled. In this environment, it is vital for a value investor to maintain clear standards. Don't abandon your P/E, P/B or dividend yield parameters out of sheer frustration. Pursue your research and wait until a truly exceptional value appears. Value investing is about patience-- waiting for the right opportunity to buy stock and waiting for the market to recognize the value of it.
</p>
]]>
</content>
<status>approved</status>
<goLiveDate>11/18/1999 00:00:00</goLiveDate>
</newsarticle>
<!-- @version $Id: //product/DSS/version/10.0.3/release/DSSJ2EEDemo/j2ee-apps/QuincyFunds/web-app/repositories/News/de_DE/growthvsvalue.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
