<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<newsarticle>

  <author>Charlie Hunter</author>
  <headline>New Keogh IRA Plan</headline>
  <date>11/18/1999 00:00:00</date>
  <targets>tax</targets>
  <language>de_DE</language>

  <content><![CDATA[
<p>
QUINCY, MA Quincy announces their new Keough IRA Plan, so if you own a small business and don't have a retirement plan, don't miss out on one of the best tax-savings opportunities available to you. The word on the street is that if the plan that you choose is not the new Keogh, you may not be getting the most benefit you can under current tax laws. There are two basic types of employer-funded small business retirement plans: simplified employee pension (SEP) plans and Keoghs. (A third retirement option, the SIMPLE IRA, is a salary reduction plan funded primarily by employee contributions.) Of these, SEPs are both more publicized and more popular. But for many small business owners, a Keogh may offer potential advantages that SEPs do not, including:
</p>

<p>
<ul type="square">
  <li>Higher contribution limits</li>
<li>Potentially greater tax savings</li>
<li>More flexibility to exclude part-time or seasonal employees</li>
</ul>
</p>

<p>
Higher contribution limits
</p>

<p>
Both SEPs and Keoghs allow you make annual retirement contributions on behalf of each eligible employee (including yourself). With a SEP, you can contribute as much as 15 percent of earned income up to <dollar/>160,000 each year, or a maximum contribution of <dollar/>24,000. But with a Keogh, you have the flexibility to contribute up to 25 percent of earned income up to <dollar/>160,000, with a maximum contribution of <dollar/>30,000 per year. If you're interested in putting as much as possible aside for your retirement, a Keogh can beef up your saving power. And because money in a SEP or Keogh is not subject to current income taxes, your retirement savings can accumulate faster than they would in a comparable taxable account. And, of course, the more you are able to contribute, the more benefit you get from this tax-deferred growth. There is a catch, however, to a Keogh's higher contribution limits. If you decide to contribute the full 25 percent, you must commit to a fixed contribution of at least 10 percent every year. With a SEP, you can vary the percentage each year, contributing as much as 15 percent in good years or as little as 0 percent when business is sluggish.
</p>

<p>
Potentially greater tax savings
</p>

<p>
Every dollar you contribute to a Keogh, whether to your own account or those of your employees, reduces your business income, resulting in a lower tax base and, ultimately, lower taxes. While the same formula applies to a SEP, a Keogh's higher contribution limits create the potential for greater tax savings.
</p>

<p>
Greater flexibility with part-time employees
</p>

<p>
If you employ part-time or seasonal employees, look carefully before choosing a retirement plan. With a SEP, you're required to make contributions to any employee who has earned at least <dollar/>400 in any three of the past five years. For employers who prefer not to offer retirement benefits to part-time or seasonal employees, this can be problematic. But with a Keogh, you can choose to include only employees who work more than 1,000 hours in any given year.
</p>

<p>
More administration
</p>

<p>
Given the above advantages, why are SEPs more popular than Keoghs? The main
reason is the higher level of administration and government reporting
involved with a Keogh. A SEP is a simpler plan, requiring minimal
paperwork, making it attractive to many overworked business owners.
</p>

<p>
A Keogh must be opened by year-end
</p>

<p>
If you're beginning to conclude that a Keogh makes sense for your business, there's one more potential hurdle to clear. You can contribute to a Keogh up until your tax-filing deadline, including extensions, but only if the plan was established on or before December 31 of the tax year for which the contribution is being made. So to make a 1998 contribution, you would have had to set up the plan on or before December 31, 1998. If you want to make a retirement contribution that will lower your 1998 tax bill, you'll need to open a SEP rather than a Keogh. If you wish, you can then establish a Keogh during 1999 and simply make no further contributions to the SEP.
</p>

<p>
Get advice from a tax professional
</p>

<p>
To learn which type of plan makes the most sense for your business, talk with your accountant or tax advisor. Your advisor can help you evaluate the relative benefits of Keoghs and SEPs, including the costs of the additional administration that a Keogh requires.
</p>
]]>
</content>
<status>approved</status>
<authorId>jack</authorId>
  <editorId>jack</editorId>
<goLiveDate>11/18/1999 00:00:00</goLiveDate>
</newsarticle>
<!-- @version $Id: //product/DSS/version/10.0.3/release/DSSJ2EEDemo/j2ee-apps/QuincyFunds/web-app/repositories/News/de_DE/newkeogh.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
