<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<AtgNews>
<story>
<id>011</id>
<category>Portals</category>
<headline>Corporate Portals: Opening the Door to Better Business</headline>
<summary>Are you striving to use a common enterprise platform for all portal projects and reuse content and functionality across these projects? Discover how companies like Yada Yada and Barclays Global Investments are doing just that.</summary>
<content>CAMBRIDGE, Mass., atgInnovator Volume 3 Number 2 Spring/Summer 2001 - Ask most business executives today about portals and they'd likely point to such companies as Yahoo! or Excite. Indeed, during dot-com mania, these types of Internet portals garnered great media attention and organized volumes of Web-based information for consumers in exchange for traffic to their site. Traffic sold advertising and advertising generated revenue. 
However, these examples represent only one type of portal in the industry today. Says Tom Carlin, director of product management at ATG, "At any one time, people have understood portals in a variety of contexts. Certainly the dot-com phase highlighted consumer-oriented portals. Now corporate portals are the buzz of the day." 
Analysts see the implementation of corporate portals on the rise by companies across all industries. More than half of companies surveyed by The Delphi Group, a global business and IT advisory services organization, showed that customer and employee portals were under consideration. Another 30 percent said they were at some stage in deployment, from evaluating vendors to launching portal projects. 
Why the buzz? Portals are helping to solve basic communication problems, says Mark Tucker, a senior consultant with The Delphi Group. "The biggest problem is not lack of information, it is lack of contextualized information. Most people who are investing in portals agree that they're trying to help people out of this 'infoglut.' We can't find what we need without having to look through 40 other things that we don't need." 
Portals also are providing a framework through which companies can create a rich interaction with each individual user. Allan Sontra, channel manager with VeriSign Consulting, the professional services division of VeriSign, Inc., explains: "What you're doing is building a tighter relationship between that entity and your organization. Portals are capable of providing immediate access to multiple pieces of information that have a higher probability of being useful to each employee, customer, or partner." 
So what exactly is a corporate portal? "Think of it as a digital dashboard," advises Jay Wiegmann, a senior consultant with VeriSign Consulting, "When you're driving down the road you don't want to switch screens to find out how much gas you have, what your speed is, and whether you're overheating or not. A portal provides a digital dashboard for your business." 
It's a familiar concept, says Tucker. "If you think of a portal as a single point of personalized access to business information, that concept has been around for a long time. We've tried it in a number of ways in the past, with the Web or with workflow management software, but the problem is that with so many disparate information sources, it has been hard to bring them together into a single point of access." 
Today's corporate portals are finally helping companies make headway in this area, and create one-to-one relationships that help users access the information they need. Whether designed for employees, customers, or partners - all share four basic characteristics. First, they support the aggregation of content from internal sources, such as CRM (customer relationship management) and account support applications, and from external sources, such as news services. Second, they deliver role-based access, ensuring the right people see the right content, based on their affiliation with the corporation. Third, they provide personalized information based on the user's preferences. Those preferences may be stated up-front at registration, or gleaned over time based on the user's interaction with the portal. And finally, they offer a community that supports dialogue and collaboration. An internal portal may include a discussion board so users can collaborate and share ideas, while an external portal may provide a forum for customers and partners to learn directly from company experts. The sum is simplifying information access for users and delivering information in a context that is valuable to the user.

Yada Yada - not just a lot of talk



YadaYada, a wireless Internet service provider, for example, launched an external portal designed to help the company increase subscriptions to its wireless services. This free service, called My YadaYada, provides mobile business executives and consumers with access to the entire Internet in a context that's meaningful for them. 
My YadaYada is no ordinary Internet portal. Users can personalize preferences and information sources from their desktop PC as well as from any wireless or modem-based device and consolidate information from all of their PIM (personal information management) applications and e-mail systems, under a single, unified window. With My YadaYada, an executive with multiple e-mail accounts doesn't need to click open several applications on his PDA to check his e-mail while traveling. And if his secretary has updated his calendar, he simply taps the "YadaYada Sync" icon with his stylus and his calendars are automatically synchronized. 
Says Raj Gupta, president of YadaYada: "The world is moving to the Internet and we are moving the Internet into your pocket. That is a very powerful proposition. But now that we've done this, we give users as much capability as possible to customize and personalize the Internet." For YadaYada, easy access to information was a key consideration in launching the portal. What mobile user wants to be standing on a street corner tapping away on the screen to find information? As a result, the portal is designed to deliver information within three clicks at most. "Maximum is three clicks to get to where you want to go. If it's more than three, it's not going to work," explains Gupta. 
Why launch the portal? You can't have a car without tires, Gupta says. Likewise, the portal is integral to YadaYada's business. "The portal makes our service more useful. More people want to use the service and more people want the service because they want the portal."

Online relationship management at Barclays Global Investors



Similarly, Barclays Global Investors (BGI), the world's largest institutional manager and largest provider of structured investment strategies, saw portals as a way to enrich their relationships with all audiences - employees, customers, partners, and potential clients. To that end, they've launchedthree portals, all intended to provide each user with a personalized experience through a single window to the organization. 
First to hit the airwaves was BGI's information pipeline, known as bip, which replaced a static Intranet site that was minimally used. bip offers employees a single source for company news along with a host of productivity tools such as a searchable online employee directory, a global clock that helps users set up meetings worldwide, and a global travel toolkit, which provides users practical and cultural information for different regions. For employee portals like bip, better communication and better access to resources ultimately improve productivity and reduce the cost of doing business. 
"Our goal was to inform, connect, and inspire employees," says Michele Wolpe, BGI's manager of Global Internal Communications. "People who feel better connected and are more informed and can get their jobs done easier are more productive, empowered, and happier employees." 
To that end, personalization was key. Explains Wolpe: "With personalization, we've been able to create a site where you get your regional news on the front page based on where you live." Users can also subscribe to news from other regions or various business units, depending on their need, with all information being displayed on their desktop. The overall internal communications impact has been huge, says Wolpe. Almost 85 percent of users surveyed said that bip has made a difference in BGI's internal communication. "People felt that they knew much better what was going on and that they could find people much easier. 
"Our whole culture has become more open," continued Wolpe. "Before, regions would communicate within their regions, but you wouldn't necessarily share that information globally. There's a lot of benefit to global sharing, with opportunities to leverage ideas so you don't have to reinvent the wheel every time."

A springboard to its customer portal



Just recently BGI launched a newly designed barclaysglobal.com, delivering to customers and partners worldwide a truly customized experience. Says Kathy Taylor, head of global marketing for BGI, "We are definitely a global organization. It's not just in our name. And the needs of each of our offices and the markets they serve are very different. So when we wanted to redesign the site, we realized we needed to rely very heavily on personalizationcapabilities." 
The company used bip as a test bed for the personalization technology, before launching it at barclaysglobal.com. "We identified personalization as a major goal for the firm, especially for our customer site, and used our internal site to learn how to incorporate personalization before going out with it externally," says Wolpe. 
With personalization, BGI is able to deliver to clients product and service information specific to their region along with product and research updates of interest to them. For example, if a market crisis arises in a specific region, the company now has the capability to quickly publish a research report and "push" that information to clients who may be impacted. And this is only the first step, says Taylor. "Today, in the password-protected environment we know who the client is and what type of investor they are so we're able to custom serve information at that level. Going forward, we plan to extend this capability to prospective clients so we can give them content specially targeted to what they tell us about themselves and their investment needs." 
The site aggregates content from a variety of internal applications so clients can review detailed information on their accounts. Clients can see how many units they hold, the most recent unit and market values, the actual holdings within the funds, their pro rata share of each of those holdings, the actual underlying shares that those units of the funds represent, and their exposure to a given stock or bond across all of their plans. 
According to Taylor, barclaysglobal.com is expected to improve customer service and decrease operating costs. "It makes it much easier to do business with us, helps us really show the value that we have as an organization and potentially reduces the cost to service each client."

A product-specific portal



At the same time, the company launched its third portal - iShares.com. It's a product marketing tool designed to market the company's iShares family of funds to three different audiences - individual investors, institutional investors/brokers, and registered investment advisors. 
iShares are part of a new breed of mutual fund called exchange-traded funds (ETFs), which are set up like mutual funds but traded like individual stocks. Because ETFs are a new concept in trading, BGI needed a way to educate clients and prospects and help build a community of interested investors. "It will close the gap between what we know and what we don't know about our investors," says Jeff Torchon, Internet manager for BGI's U.S. Individual Investor business. "The information we'll get from the site will help us understand not only the types of investors interested in our products but also the types of content they are interested in." 
While much information is available to visitors on the site without registering, those who do register receive a host of personalized services. The site aggregates content from numerous internal sources as well as other Web sites - some of which is not publicly available and some of which is difficult to find - to provide registered users with news, statistical information, and investment tools customized to their needs. Individual investors, for example, can add a link to their online broker so they're only one click away from placing a trade. Registered investment advisors and brokers have access to sophisticated portfolio strategies and a fund finder that enables them to search for funds against specific criteria.

A platform for information sharing



At BGI, the company launched all of its portals on ATG Dynamo. As a result, according to Taylor, the company has been able to share content between portals. "Essentially, we're able to use one piece of content but put it out to different audiences. For example, we can put a career posting up on our internal site with much more detailed information than would show up on the external site so it enhances our ability to attract new people from outside in a very cost-effective way." 
Carlin stresses this need to plan for portability of information across several portals. "What most organizations are realizing is that they don't need just one portal. They need several different portals for different audiences and purposes. And the question is do you want to adopt a new platform for each portal that you implement, which incurs a lot of training and adoption costs? Or do you want to use a common 'enterprise platform' for all portal projects and reuse the integration, content, and functionality across those projects?"

Measure twice, cut once



For companies about to implement a portal, experts agree, planning is invaluable. Wolpe found up-front research critical to selling management on the idea of an employee portal. "When I was pushed and challenged on some of the recommendations, I always had research to fall back on. I could have easily done the strategy and not done the research, but I think that would have come back to haunt us in trying to sell the project." 
Strong content management, authentication, and security as well as enterprise-wide involvement from business units and the IT department are also important in the development and launch of the project. Consider where you'll pull content from - in terms of both internal and external sources and who will manage that content, what tools you can provide to drive users to your site regularly, and how users will be able to access information from different applications located in different security domains. 
For many companies, like BGI and YadaYada, corporate portals are opening the door to better business and helping to enrich interaction with customers, partners, and employees. While Internet portals like Yahoo! provide the gateway to the Web, corporate portals are providing a gateway to stronger business relationships. 
But don't be surprised if many companies don't yet classify their efforts to deliver a single unified window to customers, partners, or employees as a "portal." Take BGI. With three portals under their belt, they have yet to adopt the lingo. SaysTaylor, "We wouldn't necessarily categorize ourselves as a portal. But if you look at it from our client's perspective and asked where is the best portal to get information related to our style of investment, we would like them to respond 'barclaysglobal.com'." 

</content>
</story>




</AtgNews>
<!-- @version $Id: //app/portal/version/10.0.3/xmlfeed/xmlfeed.war/xml/LocalAtgNews/011.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
