<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<newsarticle>

  <author>Sampson Lyrret</author>
  <headline>Reassess your portfolio - still a lot of upside in Growth markets</headline>
  <date>11/22/1999 00:00:00</date>
  <targets>growth</targets>
  <language>de_DE</language>

  <content><![CDATA[
<p>
NEW YORK/November 11, 1998-Market volatility is beginning to show signs that it might be time for you to reassess your portfolio. It is becoming clear that many people are seeking out financial advice as of late, and one thing that makes this obvious is that a nationwide survey of investors reports an uptick in interest in financial planners' services over the past 6 months. The Wise Investor survey conducted by Montgomery Asset Management in November and December found one fifth of respondents (20 percent) say they are more inclined to use a financial advisor due the quarter's market actions. Overall, 65 percent of respondents said they plan to use, or will continue to use, a financial advisor during 1998.
</p>

<p>
When you first created your portfolio, it is likely that your initial asset allocation was designed so that you were both aware of and comfortable with the risks that you took on in pursuit of your goals. Over time, however, the riskiness of your portfolio has most likely changed as each wedge of "portfolio pie" (i.e., each asset category) grows more quickly or more slowly relative to the others. Since rebalancing back to your original allocation targets brings your portfolio back in line with your stated risk tolerance, it usually also re-establishes your comfort level. One suggestion that we have, is not necessarily to look for comfort when you reassess your current assets. Look to what many perceive as risky investments, growth funds. Over recent months, it appears that growth funds have been exceeding the performance levels that were expected of them. Just last year, growth funds were the top performing mutual funds in all four quarters.
</p>

<p>
For those not in the know, growth refers to stocks of companies that are experiencing rapid growth in earnings, sales or return on equity. They tend to have price earnings (P/E) or price book (P/B) ratios that are higher than the overall market.
</p>

<p>
One precautionary measure, however, before you go out and reinvest everything in Quincy's growth funds, be sure that you don't get greedy; the good times won't roll on forever, and a rebalanced portfolio, being healthier over the long term, will generally let you sleep better even during a market downturn. The longer answer is that we won't blindly sell the "best" performer. We will revisit the fundamentals of both individual stocks and stock mutual funds--we usually can also find a negative factor--so essentially we'll try to sell the weakest link in the strongest segment. Negatives for a stock might include an overly high price/earnings ratio, an operating problem in the business, or a competitive development. For funds, a managerial change or style shift could be red flags. So we try to kill two birds with one stone: rebalance the assets while pruning out potential problems.
</p>
]]>
</content>
<status>approved</status>
<authorId>jack</authorId>
  <editorId>jack</editorId>
<goLiveDate>12/1/1999 14:00:00</goLiveDate>
</newsarticle>
<!-- @version $Id: //product/DSS/version/10.0.3/release/DSSJ2EEDemo/j2ee-apps/QuincyFunds/web-app/repositories/News/de_DE/reassess.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
