<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<AtgNews>

<story>
<id>002</id>
<category>ROIMax News</category>
<headline>
  ROIMax and Zydeco Launch Joint Product</headline>
<summary>
  Based On successful small business application, product for individuals launched</summary>

<content>
CAMBRIDGE, Mass., April 24, 2001 - ROIMax, Inc (Nasdaq: ROI) today announced the successful launch of the small business application on the ROIMax product. An innovative application developed by Zydeco for small businesses allows individuals and businesses the ability to work with the product. Launched as a joint initiative, the application is an example of how businesses can use the product to deliver fast, convenient services. Based on its successful small business application launched in March of 2000, the company brought the product to individuals in 20 weeks, offering greater convenience. 

"The application was the company's first attempt at delivering comprehensive and interactive services and it is truly groundbreaking in a number of ways," said Daniel Lawson. "We understood early on that we needed to be as flexible as possible, and develop an application that could be expanded to other types and across traditional boundaries. ROIMax gave us that flexibility, and is continuing to serve us well as we expand the functionality of the application." 

The group's goal for the application was to make the process quick and simple for its customers. Using ROIMax product, Zydeco created a site that offers businesses 24-hour access. These features all contribute to a faster process with fewer errors for. 

"When looking to create the application, we knew we wanted to work with companies that understood our needs and our business objectives," said Farley Zanhoff, Business Project Manager. "Zydeco's solid experience with implementations combined with the technology strength of ROIMax gave us just what we were looking for to complete the application. With ROIMax product, we have a solid foundation for extending the services we offer our customers." 

About ROIMax
ROIMax, Inc. is a leading provider of products and services. ROIMax offers an integrated suite of products and services, as well as related integration and support services. The ROIMax Connector product enables Global 1000 enterprises, as well as new businesses. 

The ROIMax Connector solution is designed to provide businesses with the core tools required to deploy products. Connector is licensed to over 425 customers. The company is headquartered in Cambridge, Massachusetts with additional locations throughout North America, Europe, and Asia Pacific. 

Connector is a registered trademark of ROIMax. 

# # # 
This press release contains forward-looking statements for purposes of the safe harbor provisions under The Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These statements involve known and unknown risks and uncertainties that may cause ROIMax's actual results, levels of activity, performance or achievements to be materially different from any future results, levels of activity, performance or achievements expressed or implied by such forward-looking statements. Important risk factors affecting ROIMax's business generally may be found in ROIMax's periodic reports and registration statements filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission. ROIMax undertakes no obligation to update any of the forward-looking statements after the date of this press release.
</content>

</story>
</AtgNews>
<!-- @version $Id: //app/portal/version/10.0.3/xmlfeed/xmlfeed.war/xml/LocalROIMaxNews/002.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
