<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<AtgNews>
<story>
<id>003</id>
<category>Dynamo</category>
<headline>ATG To Support BEA, HP, and iPlanet Application Servers</headline>
<summary>Move enables customer deployment of ATG Dynamo e-Business Platform and eCRM applications on major application servers, extends market reach for ATG</summary>
<content>CAMBRIDGE, Mass., July 10, 2001 - ATG (Art Technology Group, Inc., Nasdaq: ARTG) today announced plans to deploy the ATG Dynamo(r) e-Business Platform and eCRM applications on Web application servers from BEA Systems, Hewlett-Packard Company, and iPlanet E-Commerce Solutions, a Sun-Netscape Alliance, along with its ATG Dynamo Application Server. With this move, ATG will enable the support of customers' e-business initiatives in diverse technology environments. Companies can build and deploy applications such as e-commerce, portals, and relationship management on their choice of these major application servers. This announcement complements ATG's plans to enhance its eCRM suite with new applications to be announced later this year.
"We are the first vendor to commit to deploying our entire application suite on the five application servers, extending our market reach by enabling us to provide the capabilities of ATG applications to the greatest customer base possible," said Jeet Singh, co-founder and CEO, ATG. "Providing customers with more options and flexibility will make it more cost-effective for customers planning to build out their e-business capabilities using ATG's applications."
ATG plans to support BEA WebLogic Server, HP Bluestone Total-e-Server, and the iPlanet(tm) Application Server. First shipments of ATG Dynamo capable of running on third-party application servers will commence in Q4 of 2001. ATG will continue to develop and support its ATG Dynamo Application Server for customers who want to use the full Dynamo suite to run their Web sites. Taking advantage of the portability of J2EE(tm), a standard that ATG has been actively involved in defining with Sun, ATG will support these major platforms along with its own to provide a complete solution for customers.
"The ATG Dynamo Application Server was one of the first Java application servers in the market, and it continues to be a development priority for ATG," said Joe Chung, chairman and CTO, ATG. "We recognize the need to offer customers a choice, so we will also fine tune our applications to run on the major servers our customers select. By offering the best of both worlds, we are positioned to deliver our product suite to the large, installed bases of the other application server vendors as well as our existing customer base."
About ATG
ATG(r) (Art Technology Group, Inc.) provides applications and an e-business software platform for e-commerce, relationship management, and portals. Customers around the globe rely on ATG for the frontline applications that help build and manage mutually beneficial relationships with customers, partners, and employees. Deployed on the industry's most popular application servers, including the ATG Dynamo Application Server, ATG's integrated suite of Java(tm) applications is ideal for large-scale, rapidly-evolving, and customized Web interactions. ATG and its network of more than 300 committed technology and solution partners deliver dedicated services for client strategy, implementation and support. Together, ATG and its global alliance network provide the e-commerce and relationship management capabilities that generate loyalty, drive sales, and empower the world's most recognized companies to realize the full potential of their online initiatives.
Today, ATG has delivered e-business solutions to more than 730 companies worldwide including 3M, Abbott Laboratories, Aetna Services, Inc., Alcatel, American Airlines, ATandT, Barclays Global Investors, BMG Direct, Eastman Kodak, Ford Motor Credit, HSBC, J. Crew, Sun Microsystems, and Walgreen Company. The company is headquartered in Cambridge, Massachusetts, with additional locations throughout North America, Europe, and Asia. For more information about ATG, please visit our Web site at www.atg.com.
####
(c) 2009 Art Technology Group, Inc. ATG, Art Technology Group, the Techmark, the ATG Logo, and Dynamo are registered trademarks, and Personalization Server and Scenario Server are trademarks, of Art Technology Group, Inc. All other trademarks are the property of their respective holders. NASDAQ:ARTG
This press release contains forward-looking statements for purposes of the safe harbor provisions under The Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These statements involve known and unknown risks and uncertainties that may cause ATG's actual results, levels of activity, performance or achievements to be materially different from any future results, levels of activity, performance or achievements expressed or implied by such forward-looking statements. Important risk factors affecting ATG's business generally may be found in their periodic reports and registration statements filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission. Risk factors related to the subject matter of this press release include the failure to enable the applications to work with other application servers within the identified timeframes, or at all; the failure of ATG to support one or all of the major platform vendors, either now or in the future; that the ATG applications will not run successfully on one or all of the identified platforms, either now or in the future; that customers will not be able to implement the ATG applications on one or more of the identified application servers; that the application server vendors will make changes to their software to render the software incompatible with ATG applications; and the non-responsiveness of customers to multiple vendor. ATG undertakes no obligation to update any of the forward-looking statements after the date of this press release.</content>
</story>



</AtgNews>
<!-- @version $Id: //app/portal/version/10.0.3/xmlfeed/xmlfeed.war/xml/LocalAtgNews/003.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
