<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<newsarticle>
  
  <author>Cherry Blum</author>
  <headline>European markets close higher thanks to the strength of the Dow</headline>
  <date>11/14/1999 00:00:00</date>
  <targets>market</targets>
  <language>en_US</language>

  <content><![CDATA[
<p>
LONDON (CBS.MW) -- British and French stocks closed sharply higher Thursday as they tracked Wall Street's post-Rubin Dow rally.
</p>

<p>
In morning trade, London shares rebounded from a Yeltsin and Rubin driven sell off. London's FTSE 100 index closed up 113.50 points, or 1.8 percent, at 6,456.60.
</p>

<p>
In Paris, the CAC rose in quiet trade due to a public holiday in France. The Paris CAC 40 gained 61.09 points, or 1.4 percent, to close at 4,415.88.
</p>

<p>
The German markets were closed Thursday for the Ascension Day national holiday.
</p>

<p>
U.K. pharmaceuticals surge
</p>

<p>
Pharmaceutical stocks in London surged but analysts said gains by pharmaceuticals stocks are a blip in the recent sector rotation. In late afternoon trade, AstraZeneca shares were up 118 pence, or 4.8 percent, at 2577. Glaxo Wellcome (GLX: news, msgs) gained 39 pence, or 2.1 percent, to 1848. Smithkline Beecham (SBH: news, msgs) stocks rose 22.5 pence, or 2.8 percent, to 826.
</p>

<p>
On Wednesday, AstraZeneca sold its specialty chemicals unit for <dollar/>2.1 billion to a management buy-out backed by Cinven and Investcorp. Smithkline meanwhile, received confirmation of U.S. patents for its Paxil drug. A positive report for Glaxo's Valtrex drug boosted the company's shares.
</p>

<p>
Looking ahead, analysts said sector rotation will likely move money out of defensive stocks -- such as pharmaceuticals -- and into cyclical stocks such as chemicals.
</p>

<p>
"It can be considered something of a bounce. They [pharmaceuticals stocks] are fairly valued on historical measures and need good earnings news to lift them which won't come until the mid-term results in August," said Mark Becker, pharmaceuticals analyst at JP Morgan in London.
</p>

<p>
Other major gainers in London included telecom stocks which were boosted by continuing merger speculation in the sector. Colt Telecom Group (COLTY: news, msgs) led gainers. It was up 60 pence, or 5 percent, at 1250. Cable &amp; Wireless PLC (CWP: news, msgs) rose 28 pence, or 3.4 percent, to 833.
</p>

<p>
"There's a large amount of upside potential left," said Richard Crehan, U.K. equity strategist at Morgan Stanley Dean Witter in London.
</p>

<p>
The company with the heaviest weighting on the FTSE 100, BP Amoco (BPA: news, msgs), picked up 20.5 pence, or 1.8 percent, to 1114.
</p>

<p>
In Europe's currency markets, the dollar gained 0.6 percent to 121.62 yen and rose 0.2 percent to 1.8394 deutsche marks. Sterling rose 0.1 percent to <dollar/>1.6189. The euro shed 0.2 percent to <dollar/>1.0626.
</p>
]]>
</content>
<status>approved</status>
<goLiveDate>12/1/1999 10:00:00</goLiveDate>
  <targets>international</targets>
</newsarticle>
<!-- @version $Id: //product/DSS/version/10.0.3/release/DSSJ2EEDemo/j2ee-apps/QuincyFunds/web-app/repositories/News/en_US/europeanmarkets.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
