<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<AtgNews>
<story>
<id>004</id>
<category>ROIMax News</category>
<headline>
  ROIMax and Geomatrix Unveil Partnership Milestones for ROIMax Product</headline>
<summary>
  Geomatrix program certification and scalability benchmark demonstrate strong advantage</summary>
<content>PALO ALTO, Calif., and CAMBRIDGE, Mass., April 18, 2001 - Geomatrix, Inc. and ROIMax, Inc. (NASDAQ: ROI) today highlighted the advantage of their combined products with ROIMax's receipt of Geomatrix Program Certification and unprecedented benchmark results for the ROIMax product. This announcement comes as the two companies' combined advantage will be further progressed with a global marketing alliance, announced today in a separate release. Working together has earned them a reputation for delivering superb functionality, performance and scalability to customers. 

Achieving Recognition for Excellence 
To provide customers with a means for identifying high-quality sources for services and applications, Geomatrix has established the Geomatrix Certification and Branding program. As a Geomatrix Certified application, ROIMax Product conforms to the program's requirements for scalability, security and manageability. 

The strength and reliability of ROIMax Product also has been recognized by other industry analysts, which placed the ROIMax Product first among products in its March 2001 Rankings. 

Performance and Scalability Put to the Test
Together, ROIMax and Geomatrix put their solution to the test to demonstrate the inherent scalability and strength of ROIMax Product running on Geomatrix. The scalability tests were designed as a complex, fully dynamic application. The result was achieved on a realistic application using a complex combination of the features ROIMax offers in its ROIMax Product Suite. The results of the "ROIMax Product and Geomatrix Scalability Report" show that high-performance is not compromised as advanced features and incremental power are added to meet the needs of a growing customer base and evolving business environment. Other performance tests show even faster results with simpler applications. 

About ROIMax
ROIMax, Inc. is a leading provider of products and services. ROIMax offers an integrated suite of products and services, as well as related integration and support services. The ROIMax Connector product enables Global 1000 enterprises, as well as new businesses. 

The ROIMax Connector solution is designed to provide businesses with the core tools required to deploy products. Connector is licensed to over 425 customers. The company is headquartered in Cambridge, Massachusetts with additional locations throughout North America, Europe, and Asia Pacific. 

Connector is a registered trademark of ROIMax. 

# # # 
This press release contains forward-looking statements for purposes of the safe harbor provisions under The Private Securities Litigation Reform Act of 1995. These statements involve known and unknown risks and uncertainties that may cause ROIMax's actual results, levels of activity, performance or achievements to be materially different from any future results, levels of activity, performance or achievements expressed or implied by such forward-looking statements. Important risk factors affecting ROIMax's business generally may be found in ROIMax's periodic reports and registration statements filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission. ROIMax undertakes no obligation to update any of the forward-looking statements after the date of this press release.
</content>

</story>
</AtgNews>
<!-- @version $Id: //app/portal/version/10.0.3/xmlfeed/xmlfeed.war/xml/LocalBusinessNews/004.xml#2 $$Change: 651448 $ -->
